<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>buying Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[before]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perennials:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=73</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying Perennials are a great investment for any gardener. Unlike annuals, which only last one season, perennials can provide beautiful blooms year after year. However, picking the perfect perennials for your garden can be a daunting task. Here are some factors to consider before buying: Climate and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html">Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348d4f_PickingThePerfectPerennialsFactorsToConsiderBeforeBuying.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</h1>

<p>Perennials are a great investment for any gardener. Unlike annuals, which only last one season, perennials can provide beautiful blooms year after year. However, picking the perfect perennials for your garden can be a daunting task. Here are some factors to consider before buying:</p>

<h2>Climate and Hardiness Zone</h2>

<p>The first factor to consider when choosing perennials is your climate and hardiness zone. Some plants are better suited to certain climates than others, so it&#8217;s important to choose plants that will thrive in your area.</p>

<p>You can find out your hardiness zone by checking a USDA Plant Hardiness Zone Map. This map divides North America into 13 zones based on their average minimum temperatures in winter.</p>

<h2>Soil Type and pH Level</h2>

<p>The type of soil you have in your garden is another important factor to consider when choosing perennials. Some plants prefer well-drained soil, while others do best in moist soil.</p>

<p>In addition, different plants have different pH level preferences. Most plants prefer slightly acidic soil with a pH between 6 and 7, but some prefer more alkaline or acidic soils.</p>

<h2>Sunlight Requirements</h2>

<p>Most perennials require sunlight to grow and bloom. However, some plants need more sun than others.</p>

<p>When choosing perennials for your garden, make sure you pay attention to their sunlight requirements. Some plants need full sun all day long, while others do better in partial shade or even full shade.</p>

<h2>Bloom Time and Duration</h2>

<p>If you want your garden to have continuous blooms throughout the growing season, it&#8217;s important to choose perennials with different bloom times.</p>

<p>Some perennials bloom early in the spring, while others don&#8217;t bloom until late summer or fall. In addition, some plants have a short blooming period, while others can bloom for several months.</p>

<h2>Maintenance Level</h2>

<p>Finally, it&#8217;s important to consider the maintenance level of the perennials you&#8217;re considering. Some plants require more care than others.</p>

<p>For example, some plants need to be deadheaded regularly to encourage new blooms. Others may need to be pruned back in the fall or divided every few years.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Picking the perfect perennials for your garden takes some planning and research. Make sure you consider factors such as climate, soil type and pH level, sunlight requirements, bloom time and duration, and maintenance level before making your final decision.</p>

<p>With a little bit of effort up front, you can create a beautiful garden that will provide you with years of enjoyment.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html">Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
