<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>shade Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Beautiful Plants That Thrive in Shade Gardens</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/08/14/beautiful-plants-that-thrive-in-shade-gardens/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/08/14/beautiful-plants-that-thrive-in-shade-gardens/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 21:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beautiful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thrive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Beautiful Plants That Thrive in Shade Gardens Shade gardens can be just as beautiful and lush as those that receive full sun! With the right plant selection, you can create a serene and peaceful oasis in even the shadiest corners of your yard. Here are some beautiful plants that thrive in shade: Astilbe Astilbes are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/14/beautiful-plants-that-thrive-in-shade-gardens/index.html">Beautiful Plants That Thrive in Shade Gardens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64347313_BeautifulPlantsThatThriveInShadeGardens.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Beautiful Plants That Thrive in Shade Gardens</h1>

<p>Shade gardens can be just as beautiful and lush as those that receive full sun! With the right plant selection, you can create a serene and peaceful oasis in even the shadiest corners of your yard. Here are some beautiful plants that thrive in shade:</p>

<h2>Astilbe</h2>
<img decoding="async" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1521774971864-bf0e63c21bdc?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&#038;auto=format&#038;fit=crop&#038;w=500&#038;q=60" alt="Astilbe plant">
<p>Astilbes are known for their feathery plumes of pink, white, or red flowers that bloom in early to midsummer. These perennials prefer partial to full shade and moist soil conditions.</p>

<h2>Bleeding Heart</h2>
<img decoding="async" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1591189968283-a0aeba6d5c8f?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&#038;auto=format&#038;fit=crop&#038;w=500&#038;q=60" alt="Bleeding heart plant">
<p>The bleeding heart is a unique and eye-catching addition to any shade garden with its delicate heart-shaped flowers that hang from arching stems. They prefer partial to full shade and well-drained soil.</p>

<h2>Ferns</h2>
<img decoding="async" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1586766729916-e5fa6f39c5b9?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&#038;auto=format&#038;fit=crop&#038;w=500&#038;q=60" alt="Fern plants">
<p>Ferns are available in a variety of shapes and sizes, making them a versatile choice for any shady spot in your garden. They prefer moist soil and partial to full shade. Some popular varieties include the maidenhair fern, ostrich fern, and Japanese painted fern.</p>

<h2>Hostas</h2>
<img decoding="async" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1560255643-a28cde93a69a?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&#038;auto=format&#038;fit=crop&#038;w=500&#038;q=60" alt="Hosta plants">
<p>Hostas are a classic choice for shady gardens with their bold foliage in shades of green, blue, yellow, and variegated colors. They prefer partial to full shade and moist soil conditions.</p>

<h2>Hellebores</h2>
<img decoding="async" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1584675466166-bd5547f9b8e5?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&#038;auto=format&#038;fit=crop&#038;w=500&#038;q=60" alt="Hellebore plant">
<p>Hellebores are an elegant addition to any shade garden with their nodding flowers in shades of pink, white, or green that bloom in late winter or early spring. They prefer partial to full shade and well-drained soil.</p>

<h2>Coral Bells</h2>
<img decoding="async" src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1590140119844-c8adec8184d4?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&#038;auto=format&#038;fit=crop&#038;w=500&#038;q=60" alt="Coral bells plant">
<p>Coral bells have become increasingly popular due to their colorful foliage in shades of purple, bronze, green, or variegated combinations that add interest to any garden setting. They prefer partial to full shade and well-drained soil.</p>

<p>Whether you&#8217;re looking for bold foliage or delicate blooms, there&#8217;s a plant that thrives in the shade that&#8217;s perfect for your garden. With a little planning and care, you can create a beautiful and serene oasis that will be the envy of all your neighbors!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/14/beautiful-plants-that-thrive-in-shade-gardens/index.html">Beautiful Plants That Thrive in Shade Gardens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/08/14/beautiful-plants-that-thrive-in-shade-gardens/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Surprising Flowers That Thrive in the Shade</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/03/14/5-surprising-flowers-that-thrive-in-the-shade/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/03/14/5-surprising-flowers-that-thrive-in-the-shade/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 12:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surprising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thrive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>5 Surprising Flowers That Thrive in the Shade If you think your shady garden is a lost cause, think again! While many plants require full sun to thrive, there are several flowers that actually prefer the shade. Here are five surprising flowers that will add some color and life to your shady areas: 1. Astilbe [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/03/14/5-surprising-flowers-that-thrive-in-the-shade/index.html">5 Surprising Flowers That Thrive in the Shade</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64347792_5SurprisingFlowersThatThriveInTheShade.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>5 Surprising Flowers That Thrive in the Shade</h1>

<p>If you think your shady garden is a lost cause, think again! While many plants require full sun to thrive, there are several flowers that actually prefer the shade. Here are five surprising flowers that will add some color and life to your shady areas:</p>

<h2>1. Astilbe</h2>
<p>Astilbe is a stunning perennial that produces feathery plumes of pink, white, or red flowers. It thrives in moist soil and partial shade, making it perfect for planting around trees or in damp areas of the garden. Astilbe blooms in midsummer and grows up to 4 feet tall.</p>

<h2>2. Bleeding Heart</h2>
<p>Bleeding heart is a classic cottage garden plant that loves the shade. Its delicate heart-shaped flowers dangle gracefully from arching stems in shades of pink and white. Blooming from late spring through early summer, bleeding hearts can grow up to 3 feet tall and wide.</p>

<h2>3. Columbine</h2>
<p>Columbine is another old-fashioned favorite that does well in shady spots. This delicate flower features unique spurred petals in shades of blue, purple, pink, yellow, or white. Columbine blooms from late spring through early summer and grows up to 3 feet tall.</p>

<h2>4. Foxglove</h2>
<p>Foxglove is a showstopper with its towering spikes of tubular flowers in shades of pink, purple, white, or yellow. It prefers partial shade and well-drained soil and blooms from late spring through early summer. Foxglove can grow up to 6 feet tall!</p>

<h2>5. Toad Lily</h2>
<p>Toad lily may not have the most appealing name, but it&#8217;s a charming little flower that thrives in the shade. Its orchid-like blooms come in shades of white, pink, and purple with striking speckled patterns. Toad lilies bloom from late summer into fall and grow up to 2 feet tall.</p>

<p>So don&#8217;t be discouraged by your shady garden! Plant some of these surprising flowers and enjoy a burst of color even in the darkest areas.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/03/14/5-surprising-flowers-that-thrive-in-the-shade/index.html">5 Surprising Flowers That Thrive in the Shade</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/03/14/5-surprising-flowers-that-thrive-in-the-shade/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
