<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>needs Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Top 5 Tools Every Gardener Needs</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/16/the-top-5-tools-every-gardener-needs/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/10/16/the-top-5-tools-every-gardener-needs/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 19:43:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[every]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardener]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Top 5 Tools Every Gardener Needs Gardening is a great way to relax, enjoy the outdoors and grow your own food. Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned pro or just starting out, having the right tools can make all the difference. Here are the top five tools every gardener needs: 1. Garden Gloves Garden gloves are [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/16/the-top-5-tools-every-gardener-needs/index.html">The Top 5 Tools Every Gardener Needs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349234_TheTop5ToolsEveryGardenerNeeds.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>The Top 5 Tools Every Gardener Needs</h1>

<p>Gardening is a great way to relax, enjoy the outdoors and grow your own food. Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned pro or just starting out, having the right tools can make all the difference. Here are the top five tools every gardener needs:</p>

<h2>1. Garden Gloves</h2>

<p>Garden gloves are an essential tool for any gardener. They protect your hands from thorns, prickly plants and dirt while you work in your garden. Look for gloves that fit snugly but allow freedom of movement so you can easily handle small objects.</p>

<h2>2. Trowel</h2>

<p>A trowel is a small hand-held tool that is used for planting bulbs, digging holes, and weeding around delicate plants. It&#8217;s an indispensable tool when it comes to transplanting seedlings or moving small plants from one location to another.</p>

<h2>3. Pruning Shears</h2>

<p>Pruning shears are used for cutting back dead branches or removing diseased leaves from plants. They come in handy when shaping shrubs or trimming back overgrown trees as well.</p>

<h2>4. Watering Can</h2>

<p>A watering can is essential for keeping your garden hydrated during dry spells or hot summer months when rainfall may be scarce. Look for cans with long spouts that will reach into hard-to-reach areas like hanging baskets or window boxes.</p>

<h2>5. Soil Knife</h2>

<p>A soil knife is a multi-purpose tool that can be used for everything from digging up weeds to planting bulbs and vegetables in tight spaces like raised beds or containers.</p>


<p>No matter what size garden you have, these tools will help make gardening more enjoyable and successful! Happy Gardening!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/16/the-top-5-tools-every-gardener-needs/index.html">The Top 5 Tools Every Gardener Needs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/10/16/the-top-5-tools-every-gardener-needs/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[every]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardener]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perennial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=88</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow Gardening is a wonderful hobby that can be relaxing and rewarding. One of the most popular types of plants to grow are perennials, which are plants that come back year after year. They require less work than annuals because they don&#8217;t need to be replanted every [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html">The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348f8a_TheTopPerennialFlowersEveryGardenerNeedsToGrow.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</h1>

<p>Gardening is a wonderful hobby that can be relaxing and rewarding. One of the most popular types of plants to grow are perennials, which are plants that come back year after year. They require less work than annuals because they don&#8217;t need to be replanted every year, making them perfect for busy gardeners who want beautiful blooms without all the maintenance.</p>

<h2>1. Black-eyed Susan</h2>
<p>Black-eyed Susans are one of the most popular perennial flowers and for good reason. These bright yellow flowers with dark centers add a pop of color to any garden or landscape. They bloom from midsummer through fall and attract butterflies and bees.</p>

<h2>2. Coneflowers</h2>
<p>Coneflowers come in a variety of colors including pink, purple, white and even green. They bloom from early summer through fall and are known for their distinctive cone-shaped center surrounded by petals. Coneflowers also attract birds and butterflies.</p>

<h2>3. Daylilies</h2>
<p>Daylilies have long been a favorite among gardeners due to their stunning blooms that last only one day but continue blooming throughout the summer months. They come in a wide variety of colors such as orange, yellow, red, pink, purple and even bi-colors.</p>

<h2>4. Peonies</h2>
<p>Peonies are beloved for their large fragrant blooms which range in color from white to red with many shades in between. These stunning flowers bloom in late spring to early summer and make excellent cut flowers.</p>

<h2>5. Salvia</h2>
<p>The tall spikes of salvia give height to any garden bed while attracting hummingbirds with their bright tubular blooms which come in shades of blue, purple, pink and red. They bloom from late spring through early fall.</p>

<h2>6. Sedum</h2>
<p>Sedum is a versatile perennial that comes in many shapes and sizes with blooms that range from white to pink to red. Sedums are known for their succulent foliage and ability to thrive in hot, dry conditions making them perfect for rock gardens or as ground cover.</p>

<h2>7. Russian Sage</h2>
<p>Russian sage has silvery-gray foliage which makes it an excellent backdrop for other plants in the garden. The tall spikes of small lavender-blue flowers add height and interest to any garden bed while attracting bees and butterflies.</p>

<h2>8. Hostas</h2>
<p>Hostas are prized for their lush foliage which ranges in color from deep green to blue-green to yellow-gold. They make excellent ground cover and work well as border plants due to their mounding habit.</p>

<h2>9. Bleeding Heart</h2>
<p>Bleeding heart is a classic cottage garden plant with beautiful heart-shaped flowers that dangle from delicate stems like jewelry on a necklace.Their blooms come in shades of pink, white or red and appear in early springtime before the weather gets too warm.</p>

<h2>10. Daffodils</h2>
<p>Daffodils are one of the earliest signs of spring with their bright yellow trumpet-shaped flowers.They&#8217;re easy-to-grow perennials that multiply over time so you&#8217;ll have more year after year!</p>

<p>No matter what your gardening style may be there&#8217;s sure to be a perennial flower out there waiting just for you! Happy planting!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html">The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
