<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>build Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/build/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/build/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How to Build Your Own Raised Garden Bed</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/06/02/how-to-build-your-own-raised-garden-bed/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/06/02/how-to-build-your-own-raised-garden-bed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 05:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=17</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to Build Your Own Raised Garden Bed If you&#8217;re looking to start a garden but don&#8217;t have much space, or if you want to avoid the back-breaking work of traditional gardening, building your own raised garden bed is a great option. Not only does it make gardening easier, but it also allows you to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/06/02/how-to-build-your-own-raised-garden-bed/">How to Build Your Own Raised Garden Bed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64347776_HowToBuildYourOwnRaisedGardenBed.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>How to Build Your Own Raised Garden Bed</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking to start a garden but don&#8217;t have much space, or if you want to avoid the back-breaking work of traditional gardening, building your own raised garden bed is a great option. Not only does it make gardening easier, but it also allows you to control the soil quality and drainage for optimal plant growth.</p>

<h2>Step 1: Choose Your Location</h2>
<p>The first step in building your raised garden bed is choosing the location. Look for an area that gets at least six hours of sunlight per day and has good drainage. Avoid low-lying areas that are prone to flooding.</p>

<h2>Step 2: Gather Materials</h2>
<p>You&#8217;ll need several materials to build your raised garden bed:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lumber (untreated cedar or redwood is best)</li>
<li>Screws or nails</li>
<li>Circular saw or handsaw</li>
<li>Tape measure</li>
<li>Pencil or marker</li>
<li>Gloves and safety glasses</li>
<li>Garden soil and compost mix (enough to fill your bed)</li>
<li>Plants or seeds of your choice</li>
</ul>

<h2>Step 3: Measure and Cut Lumber </h2>

<p>Measure and cut your lumber according to the size of your desired raised garden bed. A standard size for a beginner&#8217;s raised-bed is four feet wide by eight feet long with a height of about two feet.</p>

<h2>Step 4: Assemble Your Garden Bed </h2>

<p>Lay out the cut pieces on flat ground in the desired shape. Then screw or nail them together at each corner until all sides are secure.</p>


<h2>Step 5: Fill with Soil and Plant Your Garden</h2>

<p>Fill the bed with a mixture of garden soil and compost until it&#8217;s about two-thirds full. Then, plant your desired plants or seeds according to their spacing and depth requirements.</p>


<h2>Step 6: Water and Maintain </h2>

<p>Make sure to keep your raised garden bed moist by watering regularly. Also, be sure to add fresh compost annually for optimal plant growth.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>A raised garden bed is an excellent option for anyone who wants to start gardening but doesn&#8217;t have much space or wants to avoid the physical strain of traditional gardening. By following these simple steps, you can build your own raised garden bed and enjoy the benefits of fresh produce right in your backyard.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/06/02/how-to-build-your-own-raised-garden-bed/">How to Build Your Own Raised Garden Bed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/06/02/how-to-build-your-own-raised-garden-bed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Build the Perfect Raised Garden Bed</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/23/how-to-build-the-perfect-raised-garden-bed/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/23/how-to-build-the-perfect-raised-garden-bed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:40:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=4</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to Build the Perfect Raised Garden Bed If you&#8217;re looking for an easy and efficient way to start a garden, building a raised garden bed is the perfect solution. Not only will it provide you with a dedicated space for growing your favorite plants, but it also helps reduce weed growth and soil erosion. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/23/how-to-build-the-perfect-raised-garden-bed/">How to Build the Perfect Raised Garden Bed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/6434724f_HowToBuildThePerfectRaisedGardenBed.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>How to Build the Perfect Raised Garden Bed</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking for an easy and efficient way to start a garden, building a raised garden bed is the perfect solution. Not only will it provide you with a dedicated space for growing your favorite plants, but it also helps reduce weed growth and soil erosion.</p>

<h2>Step 1: Choose the Right Location</h2>

<p>The first step in building a raised garden bed is choosing the right location. You want to select an area that receives at least six hours of sunlight each day and has good drainage. Avoid areas near trees or large shrubs, as their roots can interfere with your plants&#8217; growth.</p>

<h2>Step 2: Determine Size and Materials</h2>

<p>Next, determine the size of your garden bed based on how much space you have available and what you plan to grow in it. A good rule of thumb is to make sure the width is no more than four feet, so you can easily reach all areas without stepping on or compacting the soil.</p>

<p>You&#8217;ll also need materials for your raised garden bed. Popular choices include wood (cedar, redwood), brick, cinder blocks, or even recycled materials like old pallets or tires.</p>

<h2>Step 3: Build Your Frame</h2>

<p>If using wood planks, cut them to size and assemble them into a rectangular frame using corner brackets or screws. Make sure everything is level before securing in place.</p>
    
<p>If using bricks or cinder blocks, stack them on top of one another until they reach your desired height. Make sure they are level by using a level tool between each layer.</p>
    
<h2>Step 4: Add Soil Mix</h2>

<p>Add soil mix into your raised garden bed frame until it&#8217;s about ¾ full. A good soil mix for raised garden beds includes a combination of topsoil, compost, and peat moss.</p>

<h2>Step 5: Plant and Mulch</h2>

<p>You&#8217;re now ready to plant your desired plants or seeds into your raised garden bed. Add a layer of mulch on top of the soil to help regulate moisture levels and prevent weed growth.</p>

<h2>Step 6: Water Regularly</h2>

<p>Water your plants regularly, especially during dry spells. Raised garden beds tend to dry out faster than traditional gardens, so it&#8217;s important to monitor them closely.</p>

<h2>Conclusion:</h2>
    
<p>A raised garden bed is an easy and efficient way to start a new garden. Follow these simple steps for building the perfect raised garden bed, and you&#8217;ll be enjoying fresh produce in no time!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/23/how-to-build-the-perfect-raised-garden-bed/">How to Build the Perfect Raised Garden Bed</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/23/how-to-build-the-perfect-raised-garden-bed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
