<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>tomatoes! Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomatoes!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[varieties]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=64</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home If you&#8217;re a tomato lover, there&#8217;s nothing like the taste of fresh, homegrown tomatoes. Whether you have a big backyard or just a small balcony, growing your own tomatoes is easy and rewarding. But with so many different varieties to choose from, it can be hard to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/index.html">Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348c93_SevenVarietiesOfTomatoesWorthGrowingAtHome.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re a tomato lover, there&#8217;s nothing like the taste of fresh, homegrown tomatoes. Whether you have a big backyard or just a small balcony, growing your own tomatoes is easy and rewarding. But with so many different varieties to choose from, it can be hard to know where to start.</p>

<p>To help you out, we&#8217;ve put together a list of seven varieties of tomatoes that are definitely worth growing at home:</p>

<h2>1. Cherry Tomatoes</h2>
<p>Cherry tomatoes are the perfect snack &#8211; they&#8217;re sweet, juicy and bite-sized. They&#8217;re also incredibly easy to grow and produce an abundance of fruit throughout the summer months. Try planting them in hanging baskets or containers for a fun and colorful addition to your patio.</p>

<h2>2. Roma Tomatoes</h2>
<p>Roma tomatoes are known for their meaty texture and low water content, making them perfect for sauces and pastes. They also have a longer shelf life than other varieties, so if you have an excess harvest you can easily store them for later use.</p>

<h2>3. Beefsteak Tomatoes</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for big, juicy slices of tomato for sandwiches or burgers, beefsteak tomatoes are the way to go. These hefty fruits can weigh up to two pounds each! Make sure they have plenty of space in your garden as they need room to grow.</p>

<h2>4. Heirloom Tomatoes</h2>
<p>If you want something unique and flavorful, heirloom tomatoes come in all sorts of shapes and colors &#8211; from yellow pear-shaped fruits to green zebra stripes! These old-fashioned varieties often have more complex flavors than modern hybrid types.</p>

<h2>5. Grape Tomatoes</h2>
<p>Grape tomatoes are similar to cherry tomatoes but have a more oblong shape. They&#8217;re great for snacking, tossing in salads or roasting. You can also dry them for a delicious and healthy snack.</p>

<h2>6. San Marzano Tomatoes</h2>
<p>San Marzano tomatoes are known as the gold standard for making pasta sauce. These long, thin fruits have a sweet flavor and low acidity, which makes them perfect for cooking. They&#8217;re also resistant to disease and pests, making them easy to grow at home.</p>

<h2>7. Yellow Pear Tomatoes</h2>
<p>This tiny tomato is shaped like a pear and has a bright yellow color that adds some interest to your garden or plate. The flavor is sweet with just enough tartness to make it interesting.</p>

<p>No matter which variety you choose, growing your own tomatoes at home is an enjoyable and rewarding experience that will provide you with fresh produce all summer long!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/index.html">Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Seedlings to Harvest: A Complete Guide on Growing Tomatoes</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/25/from-seedlings-to-harvest-a-complete-guide-on-growing-tomatoes/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/10/25/from-seedlings-to-harvest-a-complete-guide-on-growing-tomatoes/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 11:02:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[complete]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seedlings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomatoes!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=97</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>From Seedlings to Harvest: A Complete Guide on Growing Tomatoes Tomatoes are a popular and versatile fruit that can be grown in almost any garden. Whether you&#8217;re an experienced gardener or just starting out, growing tomatoes is an easy and rewarding experience. In this guide, we&#8217;ll take you through every step of the process from [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/25/from-seedlings-to-harvest-a-complete-guide-on-growing-tomatoes/index.html">From Seedlings to Harvest: A Complete Guide on Growing Tomatoes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348ffd_FromSeedlingsToHarvestACompleteGuideOnGrowingTomatoes.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>From Seedlings to Harvest: A Complete Guide on Growing Tomatoes</h1>

<p>Tomatoes are a popular and versatile fruit that can be grown in almost any garden. Whether you&#8217;re an experienced gardener or just starting out, growing tomatoes is an easy and rewarding experience. In this guide, we&#8217;ll take you through every step of the process from seedling to harvest.</p>

<h2>Choosing Your Tomatoes</h2>

<p>The first step in growing tomatoes is choosing which variety you want to grow. There are hundreds of different types of tomatoes available, each with their own unique flavor, size, and color. Some popular varieties include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Cherry Tomatoes &#8211; small, sweet fruits that are perfect for snacking or salads</li>
  <li>Roma Tomatoes &#8211; oblong-shaped fruits that are great for making sauces and pastes</li>
  <li>Beefsteak Tomatoes &#8211; large, juicy fruits that are perfect for sandwiches or burgers</li>
</ul>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve chosen your tomato variety, it&#8217;s time to start planting.</p>

<h2>Planting Your Seeds</h2>

<p>The best time to plant your tomato seeds depends on where you live and what climate zone you&#8217;re in. Typically, tomato seeds should be planted indoors about six weeks before the last frost date in your area.</p>

<p>To plant your seeds:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Fill a seed tray with potting soil.</li>
  <li>Add one or two seeds per cell.</li>
  <li>Cover the seeds with soil.</li>
  <li>Mist the soil gently with water.</li>
  <li>Cover the tray with plastic wrap or a lid to create a greenhouse effect.</li>
  <li>Place the tray in a warm, sunny location.</li>
  <li>Keep the soil moist but not waterlogged.</li>
</ol>

<p>After about a week, your seeds should start to sprout. Once they reach about two inches tall, it&#8217;s time to transplant them into larger containers or directly into your garden.</p>

<h2>Transplanting Your Seedlings</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;re transplanting your seedlings into larger containers, choose pots that are at least six inches deep and have drainage holes in the bottom. Fill each pot with potting soil and gently transfer one seedling per pot.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re planting your seedlings directly into your garden, choose a sunny spot with well-draining soil. Dig a hole for each seedling that is slightly deeper than its root ball. Gently loosen the roots of each seedling and place it in the hole. Cover with soil and pat down gently to remove any air pockets.</p>

<h2>Caring for Your Tomato Plants</h2>

<p>Tomatoes need plenty of water and nutrients to grow strong and healthy. Here are some tips for caring for your tomato plants:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Water regularly &#8211; tomatoes need at least an inch of water per week, either from rainfall or watering by hand.</li>
  <li>Fertilize &#8211; use a balanced fertilizer once a month to provide nutrients to your plants.</li>
  <li>Weed regularly &#8211; keep weeds under control around your tomato plants so they don&#8217;t compete for nutrients or water.</li>
  <li>Support your plants &#8211; tomatoes need support as they grow taller. Use stakes or cages to keep them upright.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Harvesting Your Tomatoes</h2>

<p>The best way to tell if your tomatoes are ripe is by their color. Most varieties will turn from green to red (or yellow, orange, or pink depending on the variety) when they&#8217;re ready to be picked.</p>

<p>To harvest your tomatoes:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Check them regularly &#8211; ripe tomatoes can go from perfect to overripe very quickly.</li>
  <li>Pick them gently &#8211; grasp the tomato firmly and twist it off the stem. Don&#8217;t pull too hard or you risk damaging the plant.</li>
  <li>Store them properly &#8211; if you&#8217;re not going to eat your tomatoes right away, store them at room temperature out of direct sunlight until they ripen. Once they&#8217;re ripe, store them in the refrigerator for up to a week.</li>
</ol>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Growing tomatoes is a fun and rewarding experience that anyone can do. By following these simple steps, you can grow delicious, juicy tomatoes in your own backyard. Whether you&#8217;re using them in salads, sauces, or just eating them straight off the vine, nothing beats the taste of fresh-picked tomatoes.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/25/from-seedlings-to-harvest-a-complete-guide-on-growing-tomatoes/index.html">From Seedlings to Harvest: A Complete Guide on Growing Tomatoes</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/10/25/from-seedlings-to-harvest-a-complete-guide-on-growing-tomatoes/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let&#8217;s Talk Tomatoes! Growing Tips, Varieties and Uses.</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/05/lets-talk-tomatoes-growing-tips-varieties-and-uses/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/05/lets-talk-tomatoes-growing-tips-varieties-and-uses/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 07:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[let’s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips,]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomatoes!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uses.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[varieties]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s Talk Tomatoes! Growing Tips, Varieties and Uses Tomatoes are one of the most popular vegetables grown in gardens and on farms worldwide. They are versatile, healthy, delicious and easy to grow if you know what you&#8217;re doing. In this post, we&#8217;ll discuss tips for growing tomatoes successfully, different varieties of tomatoes and some creative [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/05/lets-talk-tomatoes-growing-tips-varieties-and-uses/index.html">Let&#8217;s Talk Tomatoes! Growing Tips, Varieties and Uses.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64347928_LetSTalkTomatoesGrowingTipsVarietiesAndUses.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Let&#8217;s Talk Tomatoes! Growing Tips, Varieties and Uses</h1>

<p>Tomatoes are one of the most popular vegetables grown in gardens and on farms worldwide. They are versatile, healthy, delicious and easy to grow if you know what you&#8217;re doing. In this post, we&#8217;ll discuss tips for growing tomatoes successfully, different varieties of tomatoes and some creative ways to use them.</p>

<h2>Growing Tips</h2>

<p>Before planting your tomatoes, it is important to choose a sunny spot with well-draining soil. Tomatoes love heat and sunshine; they need at least 6-8 hours of direct sunlight per day. If your soil is too heavy or has poor drainage, consider adding organic matter such as compost or manure to improve the soil structure.</p>

<p>When planting tomato seedlings or transplants, be sure to plant them deeply so that only the top few leaves are above ground level. This will encourage strong root growth and help support the plant as it grows taller.</p>

<p>To keep your tomato plants healthy throughout the season, make sure they have plenty of water (at least an inch per week), especially during hot weather. Mulching around the base of each plant can help retain moisture in the soil while also suppressing weeds.</p>

<h2>Varieties</h2>

<p>There are many different varieties of tomatoes available today, each with its own unique characteristics and uses.</p>

<ul>
    <li><strong>Roma:</strong> These oblong-shaped tomatoes are known for their meaty texture and low acidity content, making them perfect for sauces and canning.</li>
    <li><strong>Beefsteak:</strong> As their name suggests, beefsteak tomatoes are large and meaty with a sweet flavor. They&#8217;re great for sandwiches or slicing onto burgers.</li>
    <li><strong>Cherry:</strong> These small, bite-sized tomatoes are perfect for snacking and adding to salads. They come in a variety of colors, including red, yellow and orange.</li>
    <li><strong>Grape:</strong> Similar to cherry tomatoes but slightly elongated in shape, grape tomatoes have a sweeter flavor and firmer texture that makes them great for roasting or grilling.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Uses</h2>

<p>Tomatoes are incredibly versatile and can be used in many different ways. Here are just a few ideas:</p>

<ul>
    <li>Salsa: Chop up some fresh tomatoes with onions, garlic, cilantro and lime juice for a delicious salsa dip.</li>
    <li>Pasta sauce: Simmer diced tomatoes with garlic, olive oil and herbs like basil or oregano for a classic pasta sauce.</li>
    <li>Bloody Marys: Use tomato juice as the base for this classic cocktail along with vodka, Worcestershire sauce and spices like celery salt or hot sauce.</li>
    <li>Caponata: This Italian dish combines roasted eggplant, peppers and onions with chopped tomatoes for a savory appetizer or side dish.</li>
    <li>Tomato soup: Blend together cooked tomatoes with cream or broth for a comforting soup on chilly days.</li>
</ul>

<p>In conclusion, growing your own tomatoes is not only rewarding but also healthy. With these tips on how to grow them successfully plus some creative ideas on how to use them in your kitchen, you&#8217;ll be able to enjoy the fruits of your labor all summer long!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/05/lets-talk-tomatoes-growing-tips-varieties-and-uses/index.html">Let&#8217;s Talk Tomatoes! Growing Tips, Varieties and Uses.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/05/lets-talk-tomatoes-growing-tips-varieties-and-uses/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
