<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>worth Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/worth/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/worth/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:48:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomatoes!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[varieties]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=64</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home If you&#8217;re a tomato lover, there&#8217;s nothing like the taste of fresh, homegrown tomatoes. Whether you have a big backyard or just a small balcony, growing your own tomatoes is easy and rewarding. But with so many different varieties to choose from, it can be hard to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/">Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348c93_SevenVarietiesOfTomatoesWorthGrowingAtHome.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re a tomato lover, there&#8217;s nothing like the taste of fresh, homegrown tomatoes. Whether you have a big backyard or just a small balcony, growing your own tomatoes is easy and rewarding. But with so many different varieties to choose from, it can be hard to know where to start.</p>

<p>To help you out, we&#8217;ve put together a list of seven varieties of tomatoes that are definitely worth growing at home:</p>

<h2>1. Cherry Tomatoes</h2>
<p>Cherry tomatoes are the perfect snack &#8211; they&#8217;re sweet, juicy and bite-sized. They&#8217;re also incredibly easy to grow and produce an abundance of fruit throughout the summer months. Try planting them in hanging baskets or containers for a fun and colorful addition to your patio.</p>

<h2>2. Roma Tomatoes</h2>
<p>Roma tomatoes are known for their meaty texture and low water content, making them perfect for sauces and pastes. They also have a longer shelf life than other varieties, so if you have an excess harvest you can easily store them for later use.</p>

<h2>3. Beefsteak Tomatoes</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for big, juicy slices of tomato for sandwiches or burgers, beefsteak tomatoes are the way to go. These hefty fruits can weigh up to two pounds each! Make sure they have plenty of space in your garden as they need room to grow.</p>

<h2>4. Heirloom Tomatoes</h2>
<p>If you want something unique and flavorful, heirloom tomatoes come in all sorts of shapes and colors &#8211; from yellow pear-shaped fruits to green zebra stripes! These old-fashioned varieties often have more complex flavors than modern hybrid types.</p>

<h2>5. Grape Tomatoes</h2>
<p>Grape tomatoes are similar to cherry tomatoes but have a more oblong shape. They&#8217;re great for snacking, tossing in salads or roasting. You can also dry them for a delicious and healthy snack.</p>

<h2>6. San Marzano Tomatoes</h2>
<p>San Marzano tomatoes are known as the gold standard for making pasta sauce. These long, thin fruits have a sweet flavor and low acidity, which makes them perfect for cooking. They&#8217;re also resistant to disease and pests, making them easy to grow at home.</p>

<h2>7. Yellow Pear Tomatoes</h2>
<p>This tiny tomato is shaped like a pear and has a bright yellow color that adds some interest to your garden or plate. The flavor is sweet with just enough tartness to make it interesting.</p>

<p>No matter which variety you choose, growing your own tomatoes at home is an enjoyable and rewarding experience that will provide you with fresh produce all summer long!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/">Seven Varieties of Tomatoes Worth Growing At Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/02/seven-varieties-of-tomatoes-worth-growing-at-home/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
