<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>keeping Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 03:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identifying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[under]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weeds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control Weeds are plants that grow in places where they are not wanted. They can be a nuisance to gardeners and homeowners alike, as they compete with desired plants for space, nutrients, and water. Weeds can also be unsightly and may reduce the aesthetic value of a landscape [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html">Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643493d3_IdentifyingCommonWeedsAndKeepingThemUnderControl.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</h1>

<p>Weeds are plants that grow in places where they are not wanted. They can be a nuisance to gardeners and homeowners alike, as they compete with desired plants for space, nutrients, and water. Weeds can also be unsightly and may reduce the aesthetic value of a landscape or garden. However, identifying common weeds and keeping them under control is essential for maintaining the health and beauty of your outdoor spaces.</p>

<h2>Common Types of Weeds</h2>

<p>There are several types of weeds commonly found in gardens and landscapes:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Dandelions:</strong> Dandelions have yellow flowers that turn into fluffy white seed heads when mature. They have long taproots that make them difficult to pull by hand.</li>
  <li><strong>Crabgrass:</strong> Crabgrass is an annual weed that spreads quickly through seeds. It has wide leaves that grow flat along the ground.</li>
  <li><strong>Clover:</strong> Clover is a perennial weed with three-parted leaves and white or pink flowers. It grows low to the ground and forms dense mats.</li>
  <li><strong>Chickweed:</strong> Chickweed is an annual weed with small white flowers. It has smooth stems and leaves that form a rosette at the base of the plant.</li>
  <li><strong>Purslane:</strong> Purslane is an annual succulent weed with small yellow flowers. It spreads quickly through seeds and forms thick mats on the ground.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Weed Control Methods</h2>

<p>The best way to control weeds depends on the type of weed you are dealing with, as well as your personal preference for how to manage them. Here are some common methods for controlling weeds:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Hand-pulling:</strong> For small weed infestations, hand-pulling can be an effective method of control. Make sure to remove the entire root system to prevent regrowth.</li>
  <li><strong>Mulching:</strong> Mulching with organic materials like leaves, straw, or wood chips can help smother weeds and prevent them from germinating.</li>
  <li><strong>Herbicides:</strong> Herbicides are chemicals that kill weeds. They can be applied as a spray or granule directly onto the weed, but care should be taken not to damage nearby desirable plants.</li>
  <li><strong>Cultural controls:</strong> Cultural controls include practices like mowing regularly, watering deeply but infrequently, and fertilizing appropriately to promote healthy plant growth and discourage weed growth.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Tips for Preventing Weeds</h2>

<p>The best way to keep weeds under control is by preventing them from growing in the first place. Here are some tips for preventing weeds:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Maintain healthy soil:</strong> Healthy soil means healthy plants that can better compete with weeds for resources. Consider adding compost or other organic matter to improve soil health.</li>
  <li><strong>Mulch regularly:</strong> As mentioned before, mulching helps prevent weed seeds from germinating and also retains moisture in the soil.</li>
  <li><strong>Avoid bare spots:</strong> Bare spots provide ideal conditions for weed growth since there is no competition from desirable plants. Consider planting groundcovers or other plants in bare areas.</li>
  <li><strong>Pull weeds early and often:</strong> The earlier you catch a weed problem, the easier it will be to control it. Make weeding part of your regular gardening routine.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Weeds are an inevitable part of gardening and landscaping, but with proper identification and control methods, they can be kept under control. Remember to use a combination of physical, cultural, and chemical controls for best results. Finally, don&#8217;t forget that preventing weeds before they appear is the most effective strategy for weed management.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html">Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keeping Chickens or Bees in your Backyard &#8211; Pros, Cons &#038; Legalities</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/13/keeping-chickens-or-bees-in-your-backyard-pros-cons-legalities/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/13/keeping-chickens-or-bees-in-your-backyard-pros-cons-legalities/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 08:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chickens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legalities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pros,]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=75</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Keeping Chickens or Bees in your Backyard &#8211; Pros, Cons &#038; Legalities Many people nowadays are interested in keeping chickens or bees in their backyard. It can be a rewarding experience that provides fresh eggs and honey, while also helping to support the local ecosystem. However, before deciding to start a backyard coop or hive, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/13/keeping-chickens-or-bees-in-your-backyard-pros-cons-legalities/index.html">Keeping Chickens or Bees in your Backyard &#8211; Pros, Cons &#038; Legalities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348d8c_KeepingChickensOrBeesInYourBackyardProsConsLegalities.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Keeping Chickens or Bees in your Backyard &#8211; Pros, Cons &#038; Legalities</h1>

<p>Many people nowadays are interested in keeping chickens or bees in their backyard. It can be a rewarding experience that provides fresh eggs and honey, while also helping to support the local ecosystem. However, before deciding to start a backyard coop or hive, it&#8217;s important to consider the pros, cons, and legalities involved.</p>

<h2>Pros of Keeping Chickens or Bees</h2>

<h3>Fresh Food</h3>
<p>The most obvious benefit of keeping chickens or bees is the fresh food they provide. Chickens lay eggs that are delicious and free-range chicken eggs tend to have more nutrients than store-bought ones. Honey produced by bees is also extremely nutritious and has many health benefits.</p>

<h3>Sustainability</h3>
<p>Raising chickens and bees promotes sustainability by reducing reliance on industrial agriculture for food production. Small-scale animal husbandry practices like these can help reduce carbon footprints by decreasing reliance on mass-produced foods.</p>

<h3>Educational Opportunities</h3>
<p>Caring for animals can be an educational opportunity for children as well as adults. It teaches responsibility, empathy towards living creatures and where our food comes from.</p>

<h2>Cons of Keeping Chickens or Bees</h2>

<h3>Noise Pollution</h3>
<p>Chickens can be quite noisy at times especially when laying eggs which may disturb neighbors who live close by if you don&#8217;t take proper measures like soundproofing the coop. In addition, bee colonies can produce buzzing sounds that may bother some people.</p>

<h3>Messy Surroundings</h3>
<p>Chickens create a lot of waste which requires frequent cleaning around their coop area; similarly with beekeeping there could be wax combs left around the hives which can attract pests like rodents or insects.</p>

<h3>Legalities</h3>
<p>Before keeping chickens or bees, it&#8217;s important to check with your local government about any regulatory restrictions. Some cities and towns have specific ordinances that regulate backyard poultry or beekeeping, including zoning regulations, animal welfare laws and permits required.</p>

<h2>Legal Restrictions of Keeping Chickens or Bees</h2>
<p>Laws regarding keeping chickens or bees vary depending on where you live. In some areas, there are no restrictions while in others there may be a limit on how many animals you can keep. For example, New York City allows up to six hens per household but doesn&#8217;t permit roosters because they are loud and aggressive. On the other hand, San Francisco has no limits on the number of hens allowed but requires a permit for beekeeping.</p>

<h3>Zoning Regulations</h3>
<p>Zoning regulations may also affect whether you&#8217;re allowed to keep chickens or bees in your backyard. Some cities only allow agricultural activities in certain zones within city limits so it&#8217;s important to check with your local government before setting up a coop/hive.</p>

<h3>Animal Welfare Laws</h3>
<p>Many places have animal welfare laws that require owners to provide adequate living conditions for their animals. This includes providing proper housing and food as well as veterinary care when necessary. Violations of these laws can result in fines and even criminal charges.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>The decision to keep chickens or bees is one that should be approached carefully after considering all aspects including legalities involved. If done properly it can provide fresh produce while promoting sustainability and being an educational experience for children and adults alike . However, before starting either venture make sure you know what kind of rules apply where you live and what steps need to be taken to stay within the law.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/13/keeping-chickens-or-bees-in-your-backyard-pros-cons-legalities/index.html">Keeping Chickens or Bees in your Backyard &#8211; Pros, Cons &#038; Legalities</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/13/keeping-chickens-or-bees-in-your-backyard-pros-cons-legalities/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keeping it Simple with Low-Maintenance Rock Gardens</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/04/09/keeping-it-simple-with-lowmaintenance-rock-gardens/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/04/09/keeping-it-simple-with-lowmaintenance-rock-gardens/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 05:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-maintenance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=35</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Keeping it Simple with Low-Maintenance Rock Gardens If you want to add some natural beauty to your yard without the need for constant upkeep, a rock garden might be just the thing for you. With their low-maintenance requirements and versatility in design, rock gardens can enhance any outdoor space. What is a Rock Garden? A [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/09/keeping-it-simple-with-lowmaintenance-rock-gardens/index.html">Keeping it Simple with Low-Maintenance Rock Gardens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643479c9_KeepingItSimpleWithLowMaintenanceRockGardens.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Keeping it Simple with Low-Maintenance Rock Gardens</h1>

<p>If you want to add some natural beauty to your yard without the need for constant upkeep, a rock garden might be just the thing for you. With their low-maintenance requirements and versatility in design, rock gardens can enhance any outdoor space.</p>

<h2>What is a Rock Garden?</h2>

<p>A rock garden is exactly what it sounds like: a garden that incorporates rocks as its main feature. These gardens are typically designed to mimic natural rocky landscapes, such as mountains or cliffs.</p>

<p>Rock gardens can be created in various sizes and styles depending on personal preference and available space. Some may choose to create a small rock garden within an already established flower bed, while others may opt for a larger standalone installation. Regardless of size, all rock gardens rely heavily on the use of rocks and other natural materials such as gravel or sand.</p>

<h2>The Benefits of Rock Gardens</h2>

<p>One major benefit of having a rock garden is their low maintenance requirements. Unlike traditional flower beds that require regular watering and pruning, rock gardens are designed to thrive with minimal intervention. This makes them perfect for those who want to enjoy a beautiful outdoor space without dedicating too much time or energy towards upkeep.</p>

<p>Another advantage of incorporating rocks into your landscaping is their durability. Rocks are strong enough to withstand harsh weather conditions and require little care over time, making them an ideal choice for homeowners who don&#8217;t want to worry about replacing plants frequently due to seasonal changes or disease.</p>

<h2>Designing Your Rock Garden</h2>

<p>The key to designing an aesthetically pleasing rock garden lies in selecting the right type of rocks and arranging them in an appealing way. One popular technique involves grouping larger rocks together while filling in gaps between them with smaller stones or gravel. This creates an illusion of a natural hillside or mountain. Another approach is to arrange rocks in a flowing pattern, mimicking the flow of water in a stream bed.</p>

<p>When selecting rocks for your garden, it&#8217;s important to choose those that are naturally occurring in your area. Not only will this help blend your rock garden into its surroundings, but it will also ensure that the rocks are able to withstand local weather conditions. In addition to using rocks, other materials such as sand, gravel or even drought-resistant plants can be used to enhance the overall look of your rock garden.</p>

<h2>Maintaining Your Rock Garden</h2>

<p>While rock gardens require less maintenance than traditional flower beds, they still require some upkeep over time. One key way to keep your rock garden looking beautiful is through regular weeding and pruning. Rocks can attract weeds just like any other type of landscaping material, so it&#8217;s important to stay on top of these pesky invaders.</p>

<p>In addition to weeding and pruning, you may also want to consider periodically cleaning and re-arranging rocks within your garden. This can help prevent soil erosion and increase drainage around plants.</p>

<h2>Closing Thoughts</h2>

<p>A well-planned rock garden can add an element of natural beauty and tranquility to any outdoor space with minimal effort required on behalf of the homeowner. Whether you&#8217;re looking for an easy-to-maintain landscaping option or simply want something unique and visually appealing for your yard, a low-maintenance rock garden might be just what you need!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/09/keeping-it-simple-with-lowmaintenance-rock-gardens/index.html">Keeping it Simple with Low-Maintenance Rock Gardens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/04/09/keeping-it-simple-with-lowmaintenance-rock-gardens/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
