<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>plastic Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:48:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 12:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plastic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reusing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters Plastic containers are widely used in our daily lives, but they often end up being thrown away after their initial use. However, these containers can be repurposed as planters and help reduce waste while adding a touch of greenery to your home or garden. In this [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/index.html">Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349146_CreativeIdeasForReusingOldPlasticContainersAsPlanters.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</h1>

<p>Plastic containers are widely used in our daily lives, but they often end up being thrown away after their initial use. However, these containers can be repurposed as planters and help reduce waste while adding a touch of greenery to your home or garden. In this article, we’ll share some creative ideas for reusing old plastic containers as planters.</p>

<h2>1. Hanging Planters</h2>

<p>If you have small plastic containers like yogurt cups, you can easily turn them into hanging planters. Simply punch two holes on opposite sides of the container and thread a string or wire through them. Fill the container with soil and add your favorite plant.</p>

<h2>2. Tiered Planter Tower</h2>

<p>You can create a tiered planter tower by stacking plastic containers of varying sizes on top of each other. Make sure to drill drainage holes in each container before stacking them together. Add soil and plants to each layer and watch your tower come to life.</p>

<h2>3. Vertical Wall Garden</h2>

<p>To make a vertical wall garden, cut off the top half of several large plastic bottles or containers using scissors or a knife (be careful!). Attach the bottom halves to a wooden board using screws or nails, leaving enough space between them for drainage and air circulation. Fill each container with soil and add your favorite plants.</p>

<h2>4. Watering Can Planter</h2>

<p>If you have an old watering can that leaks, don&#8217;t throw it away just yet! Drill small holes at the bottom of the can for drainage and fill it with soil and plants for an adorable planter that doubles as decoration.</p>

<h2>5. Shoe Organizer Garden</h2>

<p>An over-the-door shoe organizer can be repurposed as a vertical garden. Simply fill each pocket with soil and plant your favorite herbs or flowers. Hang the organizer on a fence or wall and enjoy your new garden.</p>

<h2>6. Teapot Planter</h2>

<p>If you have an old teapot that’s no longer being used, turn it into a charming planter for small plants like succulents or herbs. Fill the teapot with soil and add your plants, making sure to leave enough space for growth.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>These are just a few creative ideas for reusing old plastic containers as planters. With a little imagination, you can turn almost any container into a beautiful planter that adds life to your home or garden while helping reduce waste in our environment.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/index.html">Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
