<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>consider Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[before]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perennials:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=73</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying Perennials are a great investment for any gardener. Unlike annuals, which only last one season, perennials can provide beautiful blooms year after year. However, picking the perfect perennials for your garden can be a daunting task. Here are some factors to consider before buying: Climate and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html">Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348d4f_PickingThePerfectPerennialsFactorsToConsiderBeforeBuying.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</h1>

<p>Perennials are a great investment for any gardener. Unlike annuals, which only last one season, perennials can provide beautiful blooms year after year. However, picking the perfect perennials for your garden can be a daunting task. Here are some factors to consider before buying:</p>

<h2>Climate and Hardiness Zone</h2>

<p>The first factor to consider when choosing perennials is your climate and hardiness zone. Some plants are better suited to certain climates than others, so it&#8217;s important to choose plants that will thrive in your area.</p>

<p>You can find out your hardiness zone by checking a USDA Plant Hardiness Zone Map. This map divides North America into 13 zones based on their average minimum temperatures in winter.</p>

<h2>Soil Type and pH Level</h2>

<p>The type of soil you have in your garden is another important factor to consider when choosing perennials. Some plants prefer well-drained soil, while others do best in moist soil.</p>

<p>In addition, different plants have different pH level preferences. Most plants prefer slightly acidic soil with a pH between 6 and 7, but some prefer more alkaline or acidic soils.</p>

<h2>Sunlight Requirements</h2>

<p>Most perennials require sunlight to grow and bloom. However, some plants need more sun than others.</p>

<p>When choosing perennials for your garden, make sure you pay attention to their sunlight requirements. Some plants need full sun all day long, while others do better in partial shade or even full shade.</p>

<h2>Bloom Time and Duration</h2>

<p>If you want your garden to have continuous blooms throughout the growing season, it&#8217;s important to choose perennials with different bloom times.</p>

<p>Some perennials bloom early in the spring, while others don&#8217;t bloom until late summer or fall. In addition, some plants have a short blooming period, while others can bloom for several months.</p>

<h2>Maintenance Level</h2>

<p>Finally, it&#8217;s important to consider the maintenance level of the perennials you&#8217;re considering. Some plants require more care than others.</p>

<p>For example, some plants need to be deadheaded regularly to encourage new blooms. Others may need to be pruned back in the fall or divided every few years.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Picking the perfect perennials for your garden takes some planning and research. Make sure you consider factors such as climate, soil type and pH level, sunlight requirements, bloom time and duration, and maintenance level before making your final decision.</p>

<p>With a little bit of effort up front, you can create a beautiful garden that will provide you with years of enjoyment.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/index.html">Picking the Perfect Perennials: Factors To Consider Before Buying</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/21/picking-the-perfect-perennials-factors-to-consider-before-buying/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 19:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=50</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening If you are looking to start a garden, consider raised bed gardening. This method of gardening has become increasingly popular in recent years due to its many benefits. In this post, we will explore why you should consider raised bed gardening for your next gardening project. What is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348bb5_WhyYouShouldConsiderRaisedBedGardening.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</h1>

<p>If you are looking to start a garden, consider raised bed gardening. This method of gardening has become increasingly popular in recent years due to its many benefits. In this post, we will explore why you should consider raised bed gardening for your next gardening project.</p>

<h2>What is Raised Bed Gardening?</h2>

<p>Raised bed gardening involves planting in soil that is elevated above the ground level. The beds are typically constructed using wood, stone or concrete blocks and can be any size or shape depending on your needs.</p>

<h2>The Benefits of Raised Bed Gardening</h2>

<p><strong>1. Better Soil Quality:</strong> With raised bed gardening, you have more control over the quality of your soil. You can fill your beds with high-quality soil that is free from rocks and debris which will help promote healthy plant growth.</p>

<p><strong>2. Improved Drainage:</strong> Because the soil is elevated above the ground level, it allows for better drainage during heavy rainfall which reduces the risk of waterlogged roots and disease.</p>

<p><strong>3. Better Pest Control:</strong> Raised beds make it easier to control pests like slugs and snails because they cannot easily climb up into the garden.</p>

<p><strong>4. Easier Access:</strong> With raised beds, you don&#8217;t have to bend down as much when tending to your plants which makes it easier on your back and knees.</p>

<p><strong>5. Longer Growing Season:</strong> Raised beds tend to warm up faster than traditional gardens which means you can start planting earlier in the season and extend your growing season later into fall.</p>


<h2>Tips for Building Your Own Raised Beds</h2>

<p>If you decide to build your own raised beds, here are some tips to keep in mind:</p>

<p><strong>1. Choose the Right Location:</strong> Make sure your raised beds get plenty of sunlight and are not located in a low spot where water can collect.</p>

<p><strong>2. Use Pressure-Treated Wood:</strong> If you are using wood to build your raised beds, use pressure-treated wood which is resistant to rot and insects.</p>

<p><strong>3. Fill Your Beds with High-Quality Soil:</strong> Use a high-quality soil mix that is free from rocks and debris for the best results.</p>

<p><strong>4. Consider Adding a Drip Irrigation System:</strong> A drip irrigation system will help ensure that your plants get the right amount of water without over-watering or under-watering them.</p>


<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>Raised bed gardening offers many benefits over traditional gardening methods including better soil quality, improved drainage, easier access, better pest control, and a longer growing season. With these benefits in mind, it&#8217;s no wonder why more and more people are turning to raised bed gardening for their gardening needs.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 10:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=99</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year Gardening is one of the most rewarding activities you can partake in. Not only does it provide fresh produce for your family, but it&#8217;s also a great way to spend time outside and connect with nature. If you&#8217;re thinking about starting a garden this year, consider [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349025_WhyYouShouldConsiderRaisedBedGardeningThisYear.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</h1>

<p>Gardening is one of the most rewarding activities you can partake in. Not only does it provide fresh produce for your family, but it&#8217;s also a great way to spend time outside and connect with nature. If you&#8217;re thinking about starting a garden this year, consider raised bed gardening! Here are just a few reasons why:</p>

<h2>Maximize Your Space</h2>

<p>Raised beds allow you to grow more plants in less space than traditional gardens. By building up instead of out, you can plant more densely and take advantage of every inch of soil. This is especially helpful if you have limited outdoor space or want to grow a variety of crops.</p>

<h2>Controlled Environment</h2>

<p>Raised beds give you greater control over your soil quality and growing conditions. You can choose the type of soil that best suits your plants&#8217; needs, amend it as necessary, and avoid issues like compaction or poor drainage. Additionally, because raised beds are elevated off the ground, they warm up faster in the spring and stay warmer longer into the fall.</p>

<h2>Less Weeding</h2>

<p>Weeding is one of the least enjoyable aspects of gardening for many people. Fortunately, raised beds require much less weeding than traditional gardens. Because they&#8217;re contained areas with defined borders, there&#8217;s less room for weeds to take hold. In addition, because raised beds typically use high-quality soil mixes rather than native soil from your yard (which often contains weed seeds), there are fewer weed seeds waiting to germinate!</p>

<h2>Better Drainage</h2>

<p>If your yard tends to be soggy or waterlogged after rainstorms, raised bed gardening may be an excellent option for you! Elevated garden beds allow water to drain more quickly and easily than traditional gardens, which can be essential for preventing root rot and other moisture-related problems.</p>

<h2>Easy Access</h2>

<p>Raised beds are designed to be accessed from all sides, making it easy to tend to your plants without having to step on the soil. This not only helps prevent soil compaction but also makes gardening easier on your back and knees. Additionally, raised beds can be built at various heights, so you can customize them to suit your needs if you have mobility issues.</p>

<h2>Aesthetic Appeal</h2>

<p>Last but certainly not least, raised bed gardens are visually appealing! They add dimension and structure to your yard or patio and come in a variety of materials such as wood, concrete blocks or even galvanized steel. With a little creativity and imagination, you can create a beautiful garden that is both productive and pleasing to the eye!</p>

<p>In conclusion, raised bed gardening offers many benefits over traditional gardens: more space for planting, better drainage and soil quality control, less weeding required, easy access for tending plants with minimal strain on your body&#8217;s joints/muscles – plus they look great too! If you&#8217;re looking for a way to enjoy fresh produce this year while minimizing labor-intensive garden tasks consider trying out raised bed gardening!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
