<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>works Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 10:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[designing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[works]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You If you&#8217;re interested in growing your own food, but don&#8217;t have the space or time for a traditional vegetable garden, edible landscaping may be the perfect solution for you. Edible landscaping combines both ornamental and edible plants to create a beautiful and functional landscape that can provide [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html">Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643493f7_DesigningAnEdibleLandscapeThatWorksForYou.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in growing your own food, but don&#8217;t have the space or time for a traditional vegetable garden, edible landscaping may be the perfect solution for you. Edible landscaping combines both ornamental and edible plants to create a beautiful and functional landscape that can provide fresh fruits, vegetables, and herbs.</p>

<h2>Benefits of Edible Landscaping</h2>

<p>There are many benefits to designing an edible landscape:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Increased access to fresh, healthy produce</li>
  <li>Aesthetic appeal of combining ornamental and edible plants</li>
  <li>Better utilization of outdoor spaces</li>
  <li>Increase biodiversity in your yard by attracting pollinators and other beneficial insects </li>
  <li>Saves money on groceries </li>
  <li>You can control what chemicals and fertilizers are used (if any) when growing your own produce </li>
</ul>

<h2>Planning Your Edible Landscape Design</h2>

<p>The first step in designing your edible landscape is to evaluate your space. Consider things like sunlight exposure, soil type, drainage, and existing plant life. Take measurements of the area so you can plan accordingly.</p>

<p>Next, decide which edibles you want to include in your design. Think about what types of fruits, vegetables or herbs you enjoy eating – this will make it more likely that you&#8217;ll maintain them throughout the season. Here are some popular options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Fruits: strawberries, blueberries, raspberries or dwarf fruit trees such as peach or apple trees </li>
  <li>Veggies: tomatoes, peppers or spinach </lil
  <lil>Herbs: thyme rosemary basil mint oregano</li>
</ul>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve decided what you want to grow, consider how each plant will fit into your landscape design. Think about the color, texture and shape of both ornamental and edible plants. Consider adding raised beds or containers for a more organized look.</p>

<h2>Maintaining Your Edible Landscape</h2>

<p>The key to maintaining an edible landscape is regular maintenance. This includes watering, pruning, fertilizing and pest control. Make sure to keep up with these tasks so that your plants stay healthy and strong. </p>

<p>Also be sure to harvest produce regularly – this will help prevent any waste or spoilage, as well as encourage continued growth throughout the season.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>An edible landscape can be a beautiful addition to any outdoor space while providing fresh fruits, vegetables and herbs for your family to enjoy. With careful planning and regular maintenance, you can create a functional garden that&#8217;s both aesthetically pleasing and practical.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html">Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
