<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>planters Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/planters/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/planters/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:48:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 08:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[household]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[items]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upcycling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=71</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters Do you have some old household items that you no longer use? Instead of throwing them away, why not upcycle them into unique planters for your home or garden? Not only is this a great way to repurpose items and reduce waste, but it can [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/">DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348d14_DiyIdeasForUpcyclingOldHouseholdItemsIntoUniquePlanters.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</h1>

<p>Do you have some old household items that you no longer use? Instead of throwing them away, why not upcycle them into unique planters for your home or garden? Not only is this a great way to repurpose items and reduce waste, but it can also add a fun and creative touch to your decor.</p>

<h2>Mason Jars</h2>
<p>Mason jars are versatile containers that can be easily transformed into charming planters. Simply fill the jar with soil and plant herbs, succulents or small flowers. You can also glue pebbles or moss onto the outside of the jar for added texture.</p>

<h2>Tin Cans</h2>
<p>Empty tin cans are another popular choice for DIY planters. To create a rustic look, wrap twine around the outside of the can and tie it in place. Then fill with soil and plants, making sure to punch drainage holes in the bottom first.</p>

<h2>Buckets And Pails</h2>
<p>If you have an old bucket or pail lying around, why not turn it into a planter? This works particularly well for larger plants such as tomatoes or peppers. You may need to drill drainage holes in the bottom of the container before adding soil and planting.</p>

<h2>Coffee Mugs</h2>
<p>You don&#8217;t need fancy ceramic pots to display your plants &#8211; coffee mugs work just fine! Choose brightly colored mugs for a playful touch or vintage cups for a more classic look.</p>

<h2>Suitcases And Briefcases</h2>
<p>For a truly unique planter idea, try using an old suitcase or briefcase as a container. These work well for larger plants such as ferns or ivies. Simply fill the case with soil and plants, then leave it open or prop it up to show off your greenery.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Upcycling old household items into planters is a fun and creative way to add some greenery to your home or garden. With just a little bit of creativity, you can turn almost anything into a unique planter that will be sure to impress your friends and family.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/">DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 12:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plastic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reusing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters Plastic containers are widely used in our daily lives, but they often end up being thrown away after their initial use. However, these containers can be repurposed as planters and help reduce waste while adding a touch of greenery to your home or garden. In this [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/">Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349146_CreativeIdeasForReusingOldPlasticContainersAsPlanters.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</h1>

<p>Plastic containers are widely used in our daily lives, but they often end up being thrown away after their initial use. However, these containers can be repurposed as planters and help reduce waste while adding a touch of greenery to your home or garden. In this article, we’ll share some creative ideas for reusing old plastic containers as planters.</p>

<h2>1. Hanging Planters</h2>

<p>If you have small plastic containers like yogurt cups, you can easily turn them into hanging planters. Simply punch two holes on opposite sides of the container and thread a string or wire through them. Fill the container with soil and add your favorite plant.</p>

<h2>2. Tiered Planter Tower</h2>

<p>You can create a tiered planter tower by stacking plastic containers of varying sizes on top of each other. Make sure to drill drainage holes in each container before stacking them together. Add soil and plants to each layer and watch your tower come to life.</p>

<h2>3. Vertical Wall Garden</h2>

<p>To make a vertical wall garden, cut off the top half of several large plastic bottles or containers using scissors or a knife (be careful!). Attach the bottom halves to a wooden board using screws or nails, leaving enough space between them for drainage and air circulation. Fill each container with soil and add your favorite plants.</p>

<h2>4. Watering Can Planter</h2>

<p>If you have an old watering can that leaks, don&#8217;t throw it away just yet! Drill small holes at the bottom of the can for drainage and fill it with soil and plants for an adorable planter that doubles as decoration.</p>

<h2>5. Shoe Organizer Garden</h2>

<p>An over-the-door shoe organizer can be repurposed as a vertical garden. Simply fill each pocket with soil and plant your favorite herbs or flowers. Hang the organizer on a fence or wall and enjoy your new garden.</p>

<h2>6. Teapot Planter</h2>

<p>If you have an old teapot that’s no longer being used, turn it into a charming planter for small plants like succulents or herbs. Fill the teapot with soil and add your plants, making sure to leave enough space for growth.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>These are just a few creative ideas for reusing old plastic containers as planters. With a little imagination, you can turn almost any container into a beautiful planter that adds life to your home or garden while helping reduce waste in our environment.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/">Creative Ideas For Reusing Old Plastic Containers As Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/12/creative-ideas-for-reusing-old-plastic-containers-as-planters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
