<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>tomato Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diseases:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identifying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[treating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases If you are a gardener, you know how frustrating it can be to watch your tomato plants grow beautifully one day and then suddenly start wilting or turning yellow the next. Tomato plants are prone to several diseases that can quickly spread and kill your entire crop if not [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html">Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348c98_IdentifyingAndTreatingCommonTomatoDiseases.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</h1>

<p>If you are a gardener, you know how frustrating it can be to watch your tomato plants grow beautifully one day and then suddenly start wilting or turning yellow the next. Tomato plants are prone to several diseases that can quickly spread and kill your entire crop if not properly identified and treated.</p>

<h2>Early Blight</h2>

<p>One of the most common tomato diseases is early blight, also known as Alternaria solani. Early blight affects the leaves, stems, and fruit of tomato plants. It usually starts with small brown spots on the lower leaves of the plant which eventually turn into concentric rings with a target-like appearance. The disease spreads rapidly in warm and humid weather conditions.</p>

<p>To treat early blight:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove infected leaves immediately</li>
<li>Avoid overhead watering to prevent water from settling on the leaves</li>
<li>Spray fungicides containing copper or chlorothalonil on affected plants every 7-10 days until symptoms disappear completely.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Late Blight</h2>

<p>Late blight is another serious fungal disease that affects tomatoes. It is caused by Phytophthora infestans, which attacks both foliage and fruit causing dark lesions on all parts of the plant. Late blight thrives in cool, wet conditions.</p>

<p>To treat late blight:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove infected plants immediately to avoid further contamination</li>
<li>Avoid planting tomatoes in areas where late blight has been present previously </li> 
<li>Spray fungicides containing copper or mancozeb at regular intervals to control its spread </li>
</ul>

<h2>Blossom End Rot (BER)</h2>

<p>Blossom end rot is a physiological disorder that affects the fruit of tomato plants. It is caused by a lack of calcium, which results in sunken brown spots at the bottom end of the fruit. Blossom end rot usually occurs during periods of dry weather when soil moisture levels fluctuate.</p>

<p>To treat blossom end rot:</p>
<ul>
<li>Water your tomato plants regularly and avoid over-fertilizing to prevent fluctuations in soil moisture </li>
<li>Add lime or gypsum to the soil before planting tomatoes as these help maintain proper calcium levels</li> 
<li>Spray calcium chloride on affected plants every 10-14 days until symptoms disappear completely.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Fusarium Wilt</h2>

<p>Fusarium wilt is a fungal disease that affects the vascular system of tomato plants. It causes yellowing and wilting of leaves, starting from the bottom up. Fusarium wilt is caused by Fusarium oxysporum f.sp. lycopersici which can persist in soils for several years.</p>

<p>To treat fusarium wilt:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove infected plants immediately to avoid further contamination</li>
<li>Avoid planting tomatoes in areas where fusarium wilt has been present previously </li> 
<li>Rotate crops every two or three years to reduce soil borne diseases </li>
</ul>

<h2>In conclusion,</h2>

<p>Growing healthy and disease-free tomatoes requires proper care and attention throughout their growth cycle. Regularly inspecting your plants and identifying signs of common tomato diseases early on can go a long way towards preventing crop losses due to disease outbreaks.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html">Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
