<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>should Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 18:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[every]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin Gardening is a fun and rewarding hobby that allows you to grow fresh produce, beautiful flowers, and lush greenery in your yard. However, maintaining a garden can also generate a lot of waste – from grass clippings to fallen leaves to kitchen scraps. If you&#8217;re looking for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html">Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643492ac_WhyEveryGardenShouldHaveACompostBin.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</h1>

<p>Gardening is a fun and rewarding hobby that allows you to grow fresh produce, beautiful flowers, and lush greenery in your yard. However, maintaining a garden can also generate a lot of waste – from grass clippings to fallen leaves to kitchen scraps.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking for an eco-friendly way to dispose of this waste while simultaneously improving the health of your garden, consider investing in a compost bin. Here are just a few reasons why every garden should have one:</p>

<h2>Composting reduces waste</h2>

<p>According to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), yard trimmings and food residuals together constitute 28% of the solid waste generated in the United States. By composting these materials instead of sending them to landfill, you can significantly reduce your household&#8217;s environmental impact.</p>

<h2>Composting enriches soil</h2>

<p>The end result of composting is nutrient-rich soil that can be used as fertilizer for your plants. Compost adds organic matter back into the soil, improving its structure and water retention capabilities. This means healthier plants with stronger root systems that are better equipped to withstand droughts and other environmental stresses.</p>

<h2>Composting saves money</h2>

<p>By using homemade compost instead of store-bought fertilizers or soil amendments, you can save money on gardening supplies over time. In addition, if you&#8217;re already paying for municipal yard waste pickup or disposal services, composting at home allows you to divert some or all of this material from the landfill.</p>

<h2>Composting is easy</h2>

<p>You don&#8217;t need any special skills or equipment to start composting in your own backyard. All you really need is a container (such as a plastic bin) and some organic matter to get started. There are plenty of online resources available to help you troubleshoot any issues that may arise, such as compost that smells bad or isn&#8217;t breaking down properly.</p>

<h2>Composting benefits the environment</h2>

<p>In addition to reducing waste and greenhouse gas emissions associated with landfilling, composting also helps to mitigate climate change by sequestering carbon in the soil. According to the EPA, compost application can lead to a 5-10% increase in soil carbon levels over time.</p>

<p>In conclusion, adding a compost bin to your garden is an easy and effective way to reduce waste, save money, improve soil health, and benefit the environment. So why not give it a try?</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html">Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 19:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=50</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening If you are looking to start a garden, consider raised bed gardening. This method of gardening has become increasingly popular in recent years due to its many benefits. In this post, we will explore why you should consider raised bed gardening for your next gardening project. What is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348bb5_WhyYouShouldConsiderRaisedBedGardening.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</h1>

<p>If you are looking to start a garden, consider raised bed gardening. This method of gardening has become increasingly popular in recent years due to its many benefits. In this post, we will explore why you should consider raised bed gardening for your next gardening project.</p>

<h2>What is Raised Bed Gardening?</h2>

<p>Raised bed gardening involves planting in soil that is elevated above the ground level. The beds are typically constructed using wood, stone or concrete blocks and can be any size or shape depending on your needs.</p>

<h2>The Benefits of Raised Bed Gardening</h2>

<p><strong>1. Better Soil Quality:</strong> With raised bed gardening, you have more control over the quality of your soil. You can fill your beds with high-quality soil that is free from rocks and debris which will help promote healthy plant growth.</p>

<p><strong>2. Improved Drainage:</strong> Because the soil is elevated above the ground level, it allows for better drainage during heavy rainfall which reduces the risk of waterlogged roots and disease.</p>

<p><strong>3. Better Pest Control:</strong> Raised beds make it easier to control pests like slugs and snails because they cannot easily climb up into the garden.</p>

<p><strong>4. Easier Access:</strong> With raised beds, you don&#8217;t have to bend down as much when tending to your plants which makes it easier on your back and knees.</p>

<p><strong>5. Longer Growing Season:</strong> Raised beds tend to warm up faster than traditional gardens which means you can start planting earlier in the season and extend your growing season later into fall.</p>


<h2>Tips for Building Your Own Raised Beds</h2>

<p>If you decide to build your own raised beds, here are some tips to keep in mind:</p>

<p><strong>1. Choose the Right Location:</strong> Make sure your raised beds get plenty of sunlight and are not located in a low spot where water can collect.</p>

<p><strong>2. Use Pressure-Treated Wood:</strong> If you are using wood to build your raised beds, use pressure-treated wood which is resistant to rot and insects.</p>

<p><strong>3. Fill Your Beds with High-Quality Soil:</strong> Use a high-quality soil mix that is free from rocks and debris for the best results.</p>

<p><strong>4. Consider Adding a Drip Irrigation System:</strong> A drip irrigation system will help ensure that your plants get the right amount of water without over-watering or under-watering them.</p>


<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>Raised bed gardening offers many benefits over traditional gardening methods including better soil quality, improved drainage, easier access, better pest control, and a longer growing season. With these benefits in mind, it&#8217;s no wonder why more and more people are turning to raised bed gardening for their gardening needs.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/07/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 10:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=99</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year Gardening is one of the most rewarding activities you can partake in. Not only does it provide fresh produce for your family, but it&#8217;s also a great way to spend time outside and connect with nature. If you&#8217;re thinking about starting a garden this year, consider [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349025_WhyYouShouldConsiderRaisedBedGardeningThisYear.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</h1>

<p>Gardening is one of the most rewarding activities you can partake in. Not only does it provide fresh produce for your family, but it&#8217;s also a great way to spend time outside and connect with nature. If you&#8217;re thinking about starting a garden this year, consider raised bed gardening! Here are just a few reasons why:</p>

<h2>Maximize Your Space</h2>

<p>Raised beds allow you to grow more plants in less space than traditional gardens. By building up instead of out, you can plant more densely and take advantage of every inch of soil. This is especially helpful if you have limited outdoor space or want to grow a variety of crops.</p>

<h2>Controlled Environment</h2>

<p>Raised beds give you greater control over your soil quality and growing conditions. You can choose the type of soil that best suits your plants&#8217; needs, amend it as necessary, and avoid issues like compaction or poor drainage. Additionally, because raised beds are elevated off the ground, they warm up faster in the spring and stay warmer longer into the fall.</p>

<h2>Less Weeding</h2>

<p>Weeding is one of the least enjoyable aspects of gardening for many people. Fortunately, raised beds require much less weeding than traditional gardens. Because they&#8217;re contained areas with defined borders, there&#8217;s less room for weeds to take hold. In addition, because raised beds typically use high-quality soil mixes rather than native soil from your yard (which often contains weed seeds), there are fewer weed seeds waiting to germinate!</p>

<h2>Better Drainage</h2>

<p>If your yard tends to be soggy or waterlogged after rainstorms, raised bed gardening may be an excellent option for you! Elevated garden beds allow water to drain more quickly and easily than traditional gardens, which can be essential for preventing root rot and other moisture-related problems.</p>

<h2>Easy Access</h2>

<p>Raised beds are designed to be accessed from all sides, making it easy to tend to your plants without having to step on the soil. This not only helps prevent soil compaction but also makes gardening easier on your back and knees. Additionally, raised beds can be built at various heights, so you can customize them to suit your needs if you have mobility issues.</p>

<h2>Aesthetic Appeal</h2>

<p>Last but certainly not least, raised bed gardens are visually appealing! They add dimension and structure to your yard or patio and come in a variety of materials such as wood, concrete blocks or even galvanized steel. With a little creativity and imagination, you can create a beautiful garden that is both productive and pleasing to the eye!</p>

<p>In conclusion, raised bed gardening offers many benefits over traditional gardens: more space for planting, better drainage and soil quality control, less weeding required, easy access for tending plants with minimal strain on your body&#8217;s joints/muscles – plus they look great too! If you&#8217;re looking for a way to enjoy fresh produce this year while minimizing labor-intensive garden tasks consider trying out raised bed gardening!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/index.html">Why You Should Consider Raised Bed Gardening This Year</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/04/17/why-you-should-consider-raised-bed-gardening-this-year/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Benefits of Companion Planting: Why You Should Give it a Try</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/04/04/the-benefits-of-companion-planting-why-you-should-give-it-a-try/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/04/04/the-benefits-of-companion-planting-why-you-should-give-it-a-try/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 18:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[companion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=81</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Benefits of Companion Planting: Why You Should Give it a Try Companion planting is a gardening technique that involves planting different crops together in order to benefit each other. This method has been used for centuries and has proven to be effective in improving plant growth, reducing pest problems, and increasing yield. In this [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/04/the-benefits-of-companion-planting-why-you-should-give-it-a-try/index.html">The Benefits of Companion Planting: Why You Should Give it a Try</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348f18_TheBenefitsOfCompanionPlantingWhyYouShouldGiveItATry.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>The Benefits of Companion Planting: Why You Should Give it a Try</h1>

<p>Companion planting is a gardening technique that involves planting different crops together in order to benefit each other. This method has been used for centuries and has proven to be effective in improving plant growth, reducing pest problems, and increasing yield. In this article, we will discuss the benefits of companion planting and why you should give it a try.</p>

<h2>What is Companion Planting?</h2>

<p>Companion planting is the practice of growing different plants together so they can help each other grow. The idea behind companion planting is to create a natural ecosystem where each plant complements and supports the others.</p>

<p>For example, some plants produce chemicals that repel pests while others attract pollinators. By strategically planting these crops next to each other, gardeners can create an environment that promotes healthy growth without relying on chemical pesticides or fertilizers.</p>

<h2>The Benefits of Companion Planting</h2>

<h3>Natural Pest Control</h3>
<p>One of the primary benefits of companion planting is natural pest control. When different plants are grown together, they can help keep pests away from specific crops. For example:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Marigolds:</strong> These flowers emit a strong scent that repels nematodes (microscopic worms) which can damage roots.</li>
  <li><strong>Basil:</strong> This herb repels flies and mosquitoes when planted alongside tomatoes.</li>
  <li><strong>Nasturtiums:</strong> These flowers attract aphids away from vegetables like broccoli and kale.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Better Soil Health</h3>
<p>A well-designed companion planting system improves soil health by promoting nutrient cycling and reducing erosion. Certain plants have deep roots that help break up compacted soil and bring nutrients closer to the surface. Other plants, like legumes, fix nitrogen in the soil that other plants can use.</p>

<h3>Increased Yield</h3>
<p>Companion planting can also increase yield by improving pollination rates and reducing competition for resources. For example:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Pumpkins and Corn:</strong> These two crops grown together have been shown to significantly increase corn yields due to improved pollination rates.</li>
  <li><strong>Carrots and Onions:</strong> When planted together, these two vegetables improve each other&#8217;s flavor and growth.</li>
  <li><strong>Lettuce and Radishes:</strong> Growing radishes with lettuce helps break up soil and allows more room for the lettuce to grow, resulting in a better harvest.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Tips for Companion Planting</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in trying companion planting in your garden, here are some tips to keep in mind:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Choose plants that have complementary needs. For example, don&#8217;t plant sun-loving crops next to shade-loving ones.</li>
  <li>Avoid planting crops from the same family together as they may attract similar pests or diseases (e.g., tomatoes and peppers).</li>
  <li>Mix flowers into your vegetable garden as they attract beneficial insects like bees and butterflies which help with pollination.</li>
</ul>

<h2>The Bottom Line</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a natural way to improve your garden&#8217;s health without relying on chemicals, then companion planting is definitely worth considering. By using this technique, you can create a thriving ecosystem where different plants work together to support each other&#8217;s growth while keeping pests at bay. So why not give it a try?</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/04/the-benefits-of-companion-planting-why-you-should-give-it-a-try/index.html">The Benefits of Companion Planting: Why You Should Give it a Try</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/04/04/the-benefits-of-companion-planting-why-you-should-give-it-a-try/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
