<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>identifying Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 09:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diseases:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identifying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[treating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases If you are a gardener, you know how frustrating it can be to watch your tomato plants grow beautifully one day and then suddenly start wilting or turning yellow the next. Tomato plants are prone to several diseases that can quickly spread and kill your entire crop if not [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html">Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348c98_IdentifyingAndTreatingCommonTomatoDiseases.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</h1>

<p>If you are a gardener, you know how frustrating it can be to watch your tomato plants grow beautifully one day and then suddenly start wilting or turning yellow the next. Tomato plants are prone to several diseases that can quickly spread and kill your entire crop if not properly identified and treated.</p>

<h2>Early Blight</h2>

<p>One of the most common tomato diseases is early blight, also known as Alternaria solani. Early blight affects the leaves, stems, and fruit of tomato plants. It usually starts with small brown spots on the lower leaves of the plant which eventually turn into concentric rings with a target-like appearance. The disease spreads rapidly in warm and humid weather conditions.</p>

<p>To treat early blight:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove infected leaves immediately</li>
<li>Avoid overhead watering to prevent water from settling on the leaves</li>
<li>Spray fungicides containing copper or chlorothalonil on affected plants every 7-10 days until symptoms disappear completely.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Late Blight</h2>

<p>Late blight is another serious fungal disease that affects tomatoes. It is caused by Phytophthora infestans, which attacks both foliage and fruit causing dark lesions on all parts of the plant. Late blight thrives in cool, wet conditions.</p>

<p>To treat late blight:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove infected plants immediately to avoid further contamination</li>
<li>Avoid planting tomatoes in areas where late blight has been present previously </li> 
<li>Spray fungicides containing copper or mancozeb at regular intervals to control its spread </li>
</ul>

<h2>Blossom End Rot (BER)</h2>

<p>Blossom end rot is a physiological disorder that affects the fruit of tomato plants. It is caused by a lack of calcium, which results in sunken brown spots at the bottom end of the fruit. Blossom end rot usually occurs during periods of dry weather when soil moisture levels fluctuate.</p>

<p>To treat blossom end rot:</p>
<ul>
<li>Water your tomato plants regularly and avoid over-fertilizing to prevent fluctuations in soil moisture </li>
<li>Add lime or gypsum to the soil before planting tomatoes as these help maintain proper calcium levels</li> 
<li>Spray calcium chloride on affected plants every 10-14 days until symptoms disappear completely.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Fusarium Wilt</h2>

<p>Fusarium wilt is a fungal disease that affects the vascular system of tomato plants. It causes yellowing and wilting of leaves, starting from the bottom up. Fusarium wilt is caused by Fusarium oxysporum f.sp. lycopersici which can persist in soils for several years.</p>

<p>To treat fusarium wilt:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remove infected plants immediately to avoid further contamination</li>
<li>Avoid planting tomatoes in areas where fusarium wilt has been present previously </li> 
<li>Rotate crops every two or three years to reduce soil borne diseases </li>
</ul>

<h2>In conclusion,</h2>

<p>Growing healthy and disease-free tomatoes requires proper care and attention throughout their growth cycle. Regularly inspecting your plants and identifying signs of common tomato diseases early on can go a long way towards preventing crop losses due to disease outbreaks.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/index.html">Identifying and Treating Common Tomato Diseases</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/21/identifying-and-treating-common-tomato-diseases/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 03:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identifying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[under]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weeds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control Weeds are plants that grow in places where they are not wanted. They can be a nuisance to gardeners and homeowners alike, as they compete with desired plants for space, nutrients, and water. Weeds can also be unsightly and may reduce the aesthetic value of a landscape [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html">Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643493d3_IdentifyingCommonWeedsAndKeepingThemUnderControl.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</h1>

<p>Weeds are plants that grow in places where they are not wanted. They can be a nuisance to gardeners and homeowners alike, as they compete with desired plants for space, nutrients, and water. Weeds can also be unsightly and may reduce the aesthetic value of a landscape or garden. However, identifying common weeds and keeping them under control is essential for maintaining the health and beauty of your outdoor spaces.</p>

<h2>Common Types of Weeds</h2>

<p>There are several types of weeds commonly found in gardens and landscapes:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Dandelions:</strong> Dandelions have yellow flowers that turn into fluffy white seed heads when mature. They have long taproots that make them difficult to pull by hand.</li>
  <li><strong>Crabgrass:</strong> Crabgrass is an annual weed that spreads quickly through seeds. It has wide leaves that grow flat along the ground.</li>
  <li><strong>Clover:</strong> Clover is a perennial weed with three-parted leaves and white or pink flowers. It grows low to the ground and forms dense mats.</li>
  <li><strong>Chickweed:</strong> Chickweed is an annual weed with small white flowers. It has smooth stems and leaves that form a rosette at the base of the plant.</li>
  <li><strong>Purslane:</strong> Purslane is an annual succulent weed with small yellow flowers. It spreads quickly through seeds and forms thick mats on the ground.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Weed Control Methods</h2>

<p>The best way to control weeds depends on the type of weed you are dealing with, as well as your personal preference for how to manage them. Here are some common methods for controlling weeds:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Hand-pulling:</strong> For small weed infestations, hand-pulling can be an effective method of control. Make sure to remove the entire root system to prevent regrowth.</li>
  <li><strong>Mulching:</strong> Mulching with organic materials like leaves, straw, or wood chips can help smother weeds and prevent them from germinating.</li>
  <li><strong>Herbicides:</strong> Herbicides are chemicals that kill weeds. They can be applied as a spray or granule directly onto the weed, but care should be taken not to damage nearby desirable plants.</li>
  <li><strong>Cultural controls:</strong> Cultural controls include practices like mowing regularly, watering deeply but infrequently, and fertilizing appropriately to promote healthy plant growth and discourage weed growth.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Tips for Preventing Weeds</h2>

<p>The best way to keep weeds under control is by preventing them from growing in the first place. Here are some tips for preventing weeds:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Maintain healthy soil:</strong> Healthy soil means healthy plants that can better compete with weeds for resources. Consider adding compost or other organic matter to improve soil health.</li>
  <li><strong>Mulch regularly:</strong> As mentioned before, mulching helps prevent weed seeds from germinating and also retains moisture in the soil.</li>
  <li><strong>Avoid bare spots:</strong> Bare spots provide ideal conditions for weed growth since there is no competition from desirable plants. Consider planting groundcovers or other plants in bare areas.</li>
  <li><strong>Pull weeds early and often:</strong> The earlier you catch a weed problem, the easier it will be to control it. Make weeding part of your regular gardening routine.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Weeds are an inevitable part of gardening and landscaping, but with proper identification and control methods, they can be kept under control. Remember to use a combination of physical, cultural, and chemical controls for best results. Finally, don&#8217;t forget that preventing weeds before they appear is the most effective strategy for weed management.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/index.html">Identifying Common Weeds and Keeping Them Under Control</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/18/identifying-common-weeds-and-keeping-them-under-control/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
