<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>favourite Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Favourite Edible Flowers That Will Beautify Any Dish</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/14/favourite-edible-flowers-that-will-beautify-any-dish/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/10/14/favourite-edible-flowers-that-will-beautify-any-dish/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 20:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beautify]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[favourite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Favourite Edible Flowers That Will Beautify Any Dish Edible flowers have been used in culinary dishes for centuries, not only as a garnish but also as an ingredient. Adding edible flowers to your dish can bring color, flavor and aroma. Here are some of our favorite edible flowers that will beautify any dish: Rose Roses [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/14/favourite-edible-flowers-that-will-beautify-any-dish/index.html">Favourite Edible Flowers That Will Beautify Any Dish</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/6434910a_FavouriteEdibleFlowersThatWillBeautifyAnyDish.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Favourite Edible Flowers That Will Beautify Any Dish</h1>

<p>Edible flowers have been used in culinary dishes for centuries, not only as a garnish but also as an ingredient. Adding edible flowers to your dish can bring color, flavor and aroma. Here are some of our favorite edible flowers that will beautify any dish:</p>

<h2>Rose</h2>
<p>Roses are not just pretty to look at but they are also delicious. They have a subtle floral taste and scent that can add elegance to any dessert or cocktail. To use rose petals in cooking, make sure you remove the white base of the petal which can be bitter.</p>

<h2>Nasturtium</h2>
<p>Nasturtiums come in a range of bright colors from yellow to deep red and have a peppery flavor similar to watercress. The entire flower is edible including the leaves which can be added to salads for an extra punch of flavor.</p>

<h2>Lavender</h2>
<p>Lavender has a sweet floral flavor with hints of citrus and mint making it perfect for both sweet and savory dishes. It pairs well with chocolate, lemon, honey and goat cheese.</p>

<h2>Pansy</h2>
<p>Pansies come in various shades of purple, blue, yellow and pink making them perfect for adding color to salads or desserts. They have a mild wintergreen flavor which complements fruits like strawberries and peaches.</p>

<h2>Chrysanthemum</h2>
<p>Chrysanthemums come in different colors including white, yellow and orange-red. They have a slightly bitter taste similar to chamomile tea making them great for brewing tea or adding into stir-fries.</p>

<h2>Hibiscus</h2>
<p>Hibiscus flowers have a tart cranberry-like flavor that can add a pop of color and tangy taste to your dish. They are commonly used in teas, cocktails and desserts.</p>

<h2>Calendula</h2>
<p>Calendulas have a slightly bitter taste with notes of saffron making them great for adding into rice dishes or soups. They also have anti-inflammatory properties which can be beneficial for digestion.</p>

<p>Edible flowers not only add beauty to your dishes but also provide health benefits. However, it&#8217;s important to make sure that the flowers you&#8217;re using are edible and haven&#8217;t been treated with any harmful chemicals. With these favorite edible flowers, you&#8217;ll be able to create beautiful and delicious meals that will impress your guests!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/14/favourite-edible-flowers-that-will-beautify-any-dish/index.html">Favourite Edible Flowers That Will Beautify Any Dish</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/10/14/favourite-edible-flowers-that-will-beautify-any-dish/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
