<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>fertilizing, Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Raising Backyard Chickens &#8211; Fertilizing, Pest Control and More!</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/06/raising-backyard-chickens-fertilizing-pest-control-and-more/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/06/raising-backyard-chickens-fertilizing-pest-control-and-more/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chickens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fertilizing,]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[more!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=95</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Raising Backyard Chickens &#8211; Fertilizing, Pest Control and More! If you&#8217;re interested in raising chickens in your backyard, there are a few things you should know. Not only can chickens provide fresh eggs and meat, but they also make great pets and can help fertilize your garden. Here are some tips on how to successfully [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/06/raising-backyard-chickens-fertilizing-pest-control-and-more/index.html">Raising Backyard Chickens &#8211; Fertilizing, Pest Control and More!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348fed_RaisingBackyardChickensFertilizingPestControlAndMore.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Raising Backyard Chickens &#8211; Fertilizing, Pest Control and More!</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in raising chickens in your backyard, there are a few things you should know. Not only can chickens provide fresh eggs and meat, but they also make great pets and can help fertilize your garden. Here are some tips on how to successfully raise backyard chickens.</p>

<h2>Choosing the Right Breed</h2>

<p>The first thing you&#8217;ll want to do is choose the right breed of chicken for your needs. Some breeds are better suited for egg-laying while others are better for meat production. You&#8217;ll also want to consider the temperament of the breed as some can be more aggressive than others.</p>

<h2>Building a Coop</h2>

<p>A coop is essential when raising backyard chickens. It should be secure from predators such as raccoons and foxes, have proper ventilation, and enough space for each bird. A general rule of thumb is to provide at least 4 square feet per chicken inside the coop and at least 10 square feet per chicken in an outdoor run.</p>

<h2>Nutrition</h2>

<p>Chickens require a balanced diet that includes protein, calcium, grains, and greens. You can feed them commercial chicken feed or make your own using ingredients such as corn, soybean meal, wheat, and peas. Chickens also love vegetable scraps like lettuce leaves or carrot tops.</p>

<h2>Fertilizing Your Garden</h2>

<p>One benefit of raising backyard chickens is that they produce high-quality fertilizer that can be used in your garden. Chicken manure contains nitrogen, phosphorus, potassium which are essential nutrients for plant growth. However, it&#8217;s important not to use too much manure as it can burn plants if not properly composted first.</p>

<h2>Pest Control</h2>

<p>Chickens are great at controlling pests such as slugs, snails, and even mice. They&#8217;ll happily eat bugs and insects in your yard which can help reduce the need for chemical pest control methods.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Raising backyard chickens can be a rewarding experience that provides fresh eggs, meat, and fertilizer for your garden. With proper care and attention to their needs, chickens can thrive in a backyard environment. Just remember to choose the right breed, build a secure coop, provide proper nutrition, and enjoy the benefits of having happy chickens in your backyard!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/06/raising-backyard-chickens-fertilizing-pest-control-and-more/index.html">Raising Backyard Chickens &#8211; Fertilizing, Pest Control and More!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/06/raising-backyard-chickens-fertilizing-pest-control-and-more/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
