<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>survive Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>5 Low-Maintenance Houseplants That Can Survive Without Sunlight</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/02/05/5-lowmaintenance-houseplants-that-can-survive-without-sunlight/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/02/05/5-lowmaintenance-houseplants-that-can-survive-without-sunlight/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 00:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[houseplants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-maintenance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[survive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[without]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=46</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>5 Low-Maintenance Houseplants That Can Survive Without Sunlight If you&#8217;re looking to add some greenery to your home but don&#8217;t have a lot of natural light, fear not! There are plenty of low-maintenance houseplants that can thrive in low-light conditions. Here are five options: 1. Snake Plant (Sansevieria) The snake plant is a popular choice [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/02/05/5-lowmaintenance-houseplants-that-can-survive-without-sunlight/index.html">5 Low-Maintenance Houseplants That Can Survive Without Sunlight</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348b82_5LowMaintenanceHouseplantsThatCanSurviveWithoutSunlight.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>5 Low-Maintenance Houseplants That Can Survive Without Sunlight</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking to add some greenery to your home but don&#8217;t have a lot of natural light, fear not! There are plenty of low-maintenance houseplants that can thrive in low-light conditions. Here are five options:</p>

<h2>1. Snake Plant (Sansevieria)</h2>
<p>The snake plant is a popular choice for low-light areas because it can survive in almost any lighting condition. It&#8217;s also incredibly easy to care for and doesn&#8217;t require frequent watering. In fact, overwatering can be a problem with this plant, so make sure the soil dries out completely between waterings.</p>

<h2>2. ZZ Plant (Zamioculcas zamiifolia)</h2>
<p>The ZZ plant is another great option for low-light spaces. Its glossy leaves reflect light well and it can go weeks without watering, making it perfect for busy or forgetful plant owners. Just be careful not to overwater this one either, as too much moisture can cause root rot.</p>

<h2>3. Pothos (Epipremnum aureum)</h2>
<p>Pothos plants are known for their trailing vines and attractive heart-shaped leaves. They&#8217;re also incredibly versatile when it comes to lighting &#8211; they can survive in anything from bright indirect sunlight to almost complete darkness. Plus, they&#8217;re easy to propagate by rooting cuttings in water!</p>

<h2>4. Chinese Evergreen (Aglaonema)</h2>
<p>The Chinese evergreen is a sturdy plant that doesn&#8217;t require much attention &#8211; just make sure its soil stays moist but not soggy and keep it away from direct sunlight. It also has air-purifying properties, according to NASA&#8217;s Clean Air Study.</p>

<h2>5. Cast Iron Plant (Aspidistra elatior)</h2>
<p>The cast iron plant lives up to its name &#8211; it&#8217;s incredibly tough and can survive in almost any conditions, including low-light areas. It doesn&#8217;t require much watering, but make sure its soil doesn&#8217;t dry out completely.</p>

<p>With these five low-maintenance houseplants, you can bring some greenery into your home without worrying about giving them too much sunlight. Just remember to check their water levels occasionally and enjoy the beauty they bring to your space!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/02/05/5-lowmaintenance-houseplants-that-can-survive-without-sunlight/index.html">5 Low-Maintenance Houseplants That Can Survive Without Sunlight</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/02/05/5-lowmaintenance-houseplants-that-can-survive-without-sunlight/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
