<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>bloom Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 16:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-maintenance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perennials:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long Summer is a great time to enjoy your garden, but it can be challenging to keep plants looking healthy and blooming for the entire season. If you&#8217;re looking for easy-to-grow perennials that require minimal care and bloom all summer long, then you&#8217;ve come to the right place! Here [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html">Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643492fd_LowMaintenancePerennialsThatBloomAllSummerLong.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</h1>

<p>Summer is a great time to enjoy your garden, but it can be challenging to keep plants looking healthy and blooming for the entire season. If you&#8217;re looking for easy-to-grow perennials that require minimal care and bloom all summer long, then you&#8217;ve come to the right place! Here are some of our top picks:</p>

<h2>Lavender (Lavandula)</h2>
<p>Lavender is a fragrant perennial that produces beautiful purple flowers throughout the summer months. These plants prefer well-drained soil and full sun, making them perfect for dry gardens or rock gardens. Lavender requires minimal watering once established and can also be used in cooking or as dried flowers.</p>

<h2>Coneflower (Echinacea)</h2>
<p>Coneflowers are hardy perennials that produce daisy-like flowers in shades of pink, purple, and white. They thrive in full sun but can tolerate partial shade as well. Coneflowers are drought-tolerant and require very little maintenance once established. Deadheading spent blooms will encourage more flowering throughout the summer.</p>

<h2>Black-Eyed Susan (Rudbeckia)</h2>
<p>The bright yellow petals with brown centers make Black-eyed Susans stand out from other flowers in any garden bed they’re planted in. These heat-loving perennials are easy to grow and will flower throughout summer until fall arrives. They prefer full sun but can tolerate light shade.</p>

<h2>Daylily (Hemerocallis)</h2>
<p>The daylily is another tough perennial that can withstand extreme weather conditions while still blooming prolifically all summer long with little care required on your part. Daylilies come in many colors such as reds, oranges, yellows, pinks, and even some bi-colors. They prefer full sun but can tolerate partial shade.</p>

<h2>Salvia (Salvia)</h2>
<p>Salvias are a diverse group of perennials with many different species available in various colors such as blue, purple, pink and red. These plants thrive in well-drained soil and full sun to part shade but will tolerate dry conditions once established. Deadheading spent blooms will encourage more flowering throughout the summer.</p>

<h2>Sedum (Sedum)</h2>
<p>Sedums are succulent-like plants that come in many varieties and sizes. They have fleshy leaves and produce clusters of star-shaped flowers in shades of pink, red, yellow or white during the summer months. Sedums require little water or maintenance once established and thrive in hot sunny locations.</p>

<p>In conclusion, choosing low-maintenance perennials for your garden is a great way to enjoy beautiful blooms all summer long without having to put much effort into caring for them. When selecting your plants, make sure they&#8217;re appropriate for your growing zone, choose varieties that suit your style preferences and soil type.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html">Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
