<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>drought-tolerant Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Drought-Tolerant Plants That Will Save You Water</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/04/24/droughttolerant-plants-that-will-save-you-water/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/04/24/droughttolerant-plants-that-will-save-you-water/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drought-tolerant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Drought-Tolerant Plants That Will Save You Water With climate change causing more frequent and severe droughts, it&#8217;s becoming increasingly important to conserve water in our gardens. One way to do this is by choosing plants that are adapted to dry conditions and require less watering. Here are some drought-tolerant plants that will save you water: [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/24/droughttolerant-plants-that-will-save-you-water/index.html">Drought-Tolerant Plants That Will Save You Water</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349349_DroughtTolerantPlantsThatWillSaveYouWater.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Drought-Tolerant Plants That Will Save You Water</h1>

<p>With climate change causing more frequent and severe droughts, it&#8217;s becoming increasingly important to conserve water in our gardens. One way to do this is by choosing plants that are adapted to dry conditions and require less watering. Here are some drought-tolerant plants that will save you water:</p>

<h2>Succulents</h2>

<p>Succulents store water in their leaves, making them perfect for dry conditions. They come in a range of shapes, sizes, and colors, from the spiky agave to the rosette-shaped echeveria. Some popular succulent species include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Aloe vera</li>
<li>Jade plant</li>
<li>Kalanchoe</li>
<li>Hens and chicks</li>
</ul>

<h2>Lavender</h2>

<p>Lavender is not only drought-tolerant but also adds a lovely fragrance to your garden. This shrub produces beautiful purple flowers and can grow up to three feet tall when mature. Lavender prefers well-draining soil and full sun exposure.</p>

<h2>Rosemary</h2>

<p>Rosemary is another fragrant herb that thrives in dry conditions. It&#8217;s an evergreen shrub that produces blue flowers in the spring and summer. Rosemary prefers well-draining soil and full sun exposure.</p>

<h2>Yarrow</h2>

<p>Yarrow is a hardy perennial with feathery foliage and clusters of tiny flowers in shades of pink, yellow, or white. It can grow up to two feet tall and prefers well-draining soil with moderate moisture levels.</p>

<h2>California Poppy</h2>

<p>The California poppy is a bright orange wildflower that blooms from spring to fall. It&#8217;s drought-tolerant and self-seeding, making it an easy addition to any garden. California poppies prefer well-draining soil and full sun exposure.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>By choosing plants that are adapted to dry conditions, you can create a beautiful and water-efficient garden. Not only will this help conserve water during times of drought, but it can also save you money on your water bill. Consider adding some of these drought-tolerant plants to your garden today!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/24/droughttolerant-plants-that-will-save-you-water/index.html">Drought-Tolerant Plants That Will Save You Water</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/04/24/droughttolerant-plants-that-will-save-you-water/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
