<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>yield Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/yield/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/yield/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 23:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[improve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[using]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield Raised bed gardening is a popular method for growing plants, vegetables and fruits in a controlled environment. By raising the soil level above ground level, gardeners can create well-draining gardens that are easier to maintain and manage. These beds are perfect for those with poor quality [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/">Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349362_UsingRaisedBedsToImproveSoilQualityYield.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</h1>

<p>Raised bed gardening is a popular method for growing plants, vegetables and fruits in a controlled environment. By raising the soil level above ground level, gardeners can create well-draining gardens that are easier to maintain and manage. These beds are perfect for those with poor quality soil or who want to maximize their yield.</p>

<h2>What is a raised bed?</h2>

<p>A raised bed is essentially a large container made of wood, stone, brick or other materials that can hold soil. They come in all shapes and sizes but typically measure between 4 to 6 feet wide by 8 to 12 feet long. The height of the bed can vary depending on your preference but most range from 6 to 18 inches tall.</p>

<h2>The benefits of using raised beds</h2>

<p><strong>Better Soil Drainage:</strong> One of the biggest advantages of using raised beds is better drainage. When you raise the soil level above ground level you give excess water somewhere to go instead of sitting around your plant’s roots which can cause root rot and kill your plants off faster than anything else.</p>

<p><strong>Improved Soil Quality:</strong> Because you’re adding fresh soil into the bed, it’s easy for gardeners to amend their soil with compost, manure or other organic material without having to till up their entire yard. This means that over time, the nutrient density within these beds will be higher than natural soil allowing for better plant growth and stronger yields.</p>

<p><strong>Pest Control:</strong> Raised beds make it easier for gardeners to control pests like slugs and snails because they have less access points compared to traditional gardens where pests can crawl from any direction at any time.</p>

<p><strong>Easier Maintenance:</strong> With raised beds, you can easily manage the soil and plants without having to bend over which is great for gardeners with physical limitations or back problems. They also make it easier to plant and harvest as you don’t have to worry about stepping on your plants.</p>

<h2>How to build a raised bed</h2>

<p><strong>Step 1: Choose your location</strong></p>
<p>The first step in building a raised bed is choosing the right location. You’ll want an area that gets plenty of sunlight but also has access to water.</p>

<p><strong>Step 2: Gather Materials</strong></p>
<p>You’ll need wood (cedar, pine, or redwood are popular choices), screws, and tools like a drill and saw if you’re making them yourself. If you’re using stone or brick, be sure to gather enough materials before getting started.</p>

<p><strong>Step 3: Cut Wood To Size</strong></p>
<p>Cut your wood pieces down to size based on how large you want your raised bed to be. A typical size is 4 feet wide by 8 feet long but this can vary depending on your available space.</p>

<p><strong>Step 4: Assemble The Bed Frame</strong></p>
<p>To assemble the frame, screw together the sides at each corner until all four pieces are connected securely creating a box shape.

<p><strong>Step 5: Add Soil &#038; Compost Mixture</strong></p>
<p>Add good quality soil mixed with compost into the bed until its levelled off evenly.

<h2>In Conclusion,</h2>

Raised beds offer numerous benefits for gardeners looking for an easy way to grow their own food without having too much hassle in terms of maintenance or dealing with poor quality soil. Creating raised beds requires some effort upfront but once built they will last for years and provide the perfect environment for growing healthy plants.
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/">Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vertical Gardening &#8211; Maximizing Space and Crop Yield</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/09/17/vertical-gardening-maximizing-space-and-crop-yield/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/09/17/vertical-gardening-maximizing-space-and-crop-yield/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 08:57:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maximizing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vertical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Vertical Gardening &#8211; Maximizing Space and Crop Yield If you are looking for a way to grow your own vegetables at home but have limited space, vertical gardening might be the solution you need. Vertical gardening involves growing crops in a vertically stacked arrangement instead of horizontally on the ground. This not only maximizes space [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/09/17/vertical-gardening-maximizing-space-and-crop-yield/">Vertical Gardening &#8211; Maximizing Space and Crop Yield</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349357_VerticalGardeningMaximizingSpaceAndCropYield.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Vertical Gardening &#8211; Maximizing Space and Crop Yield</h1>

<p>If you are looking for a way to grow your own vegetables at home but have limited space, vertical gardening might be the solution you need. Vertical gardening involves growing crops in a vertically stacked arrangement instead of horizontally on the ground. This not only maximizes space but also increases crop yield.</p>

<h2>The Benefits of Vertical Gardening</h2>

<p>Vertical gardening offers several benefits over traditional gardening:</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Maximizes Space:</strong> Growing vertically allows you to make use of all available space, even if it&#8217;s limited. You can grow plants up walls, fences or trellises, freeing up valuable ground space.</li>
    <li><strong>Increase Crop Yield:</strong> By growing vertically, you can increase your crop yield per square foot since more plants can be grown in the same amount of space.</li>
    <li><strong>No More Bending:</strong> With vertical gardens, there is no need for bending down to tend to your plants which reduces strain on your back and knees.</li>
    <li><strong>Pest Control:</strong> Since most pests attack from the ground level, vertical gardens are less susceptible to pest infestation compared to traditional gardens.</li>
</ul>

<h2>The Best Vegetables for Vertical Gardens</h2>

<p>Certain vegetables thrive in vertical gardens due to their compact nature and ability to climb. These include:</p>
<ul>
    <li><strong>Tomatoes:</strong> Tomatoes are one of the best vegetables for vertical gardens as they love climbing and require minimal support. They also provide an abundance of delicious fruit throughout the season.</li>
    <li><strong>Pole Beans:</strong> Pole beans grow tall quickly and produce large yields with minimal maintenance. They also fix nitrogen in the soil, making them a great companion plant for other vegetables.</li>
    <li><strong>Peas:</strong> Peas grow quickly and will climb anything they can find. They also produce a high yield and are rich in nutrients.</li>
    <li><strong>Cucumbers:</strong> Cucumbers are fast growers and can be trained to climb trellises or walls. They produce an abundance of fruit throughout the season and are perfect for pickling or eating fresh.</li>
</ul>

<h2>How to Start Your Vertical Garden</h2>

<p>To start your own vertical garden, follow these simple steps:</p>
<ol>
    <li><strong>Select Your Location:</strong> Choose a location that receives plenty of sunlight throughout the day. The area should also have access to water and be easy to reach for maintenance purposes.</li>
    <li><strong>Choose Your Plants:</strong> Select plants that are suitable for vertical gardening (refer to the list above). Consider planting a mix of vegetables that mature at different times so you have a continuous supply throughout the growing season.</li>
    <li><strong>Select Your Structure:</strong> There are many options available for supporting your vertical garden such as trellises, stakes, pallets, hanging baskets or even repurposed ladders. Choose one that suits your space and budget.</li>
    <li><strong>Prepare Your Soil:</strong> Make sure your soil is well-draining by adding compost or perlite if necessary. Vertical gardens require more frequent watering than traditional gardens since water drains faster from containers, so make sure your soil retains moisture well.</li>
    <li><strong>Plant Your Vegetables:</strong> Plant your vegetables according to their specific requirements (depth, spacing etc.) and provide support as needed. Water regularly and add fertilizer as needed throughout the growing season.</li>
    <li><strong>Maintain Your Garden:</strong> Regularly check your plants for pests, diseases or nutrient deficiencies. Remove any dead or diseased leaves and harvest vegetables as they mature. Prune your plants as needed to keep them from becoming too bushy.</li>
</ol>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>Vertical gardening is an innovative way to maximize space and increase crop yield while reducing strain on your back and knees. With the right location, plants and structure, you can easily start your own vertical garden at home. So get started today and enjoy the benefits of fresh, delicious vegetables all season long!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/09/17/vertical-gardening-maximizing-space-and-crop-yield/">Vertical Gardening &#8211; Maximizing Space and Crop Yield</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/09/17/vertical-gardening-maximizing-space-and-crop-yield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
