<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>summer Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 11:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hostess]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess Summer is here and it’s time to take advantage of the beautiful weather by hosting a garden party! Whether you’re planning a small get-together or a big celebration, there are some key tips and tricks to keep in mind that will [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html">Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/6434982e_PlanningThePerfectSummerGardenPartyTipsTricksFromAnExpertHostess.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</h1>

<p>Summer is here and it’s time to take advantage of the beautiful weather by hosting a garden party! Whether you’re planning a small get-together or a big celebration, there are some key tips and tricks to keep in mind that will make your party a success.</p>

<h2>Location</h2>
<p>The first step in planning your garden party is choosing the perfect location. If you have a backyard or garden, that’s an obvious choice, but don’t be afraid to think outside the box. You could also consider hosting your party at a local park or beach if they allow gatherings. Whatever location you choose, make sure it has enough space for guests and any activities you have planned.</p>

<h2>Decorations</h2>
<p>No party is complete without decorations! For a garden party, embrace nature by incorporating floral arrangements and greenery into your decor. You could even create centerpieces using flowers and plants from your own garden. String lights are also a great way to add ambiance once the sun goes down.</p>

<h2>Food &#038; Drinks</h2>
<p>A summer garden party calls for light and refreshing food and drinks. Consider serving finger foods such as fruit skewers, bruschetta, or mini quiches. For drinks, offer lemonade or iced tea as non-alcoholic options and provide beer or wine for those who want something stronger.</p>

<h2>Activities</h2>
<p>No one wants to attend a boring party! Plan some activities to keep your guests entertained throughout the event. Lawn games such as bocce ball or croquet are always crowd-pleasers. You could also set up a photo booth area with props for guests to take memorable photos together.</p>

<h2>Timing</h2>
<p>Timing is key when it comes to hosting a garden party. Plan your party for late afternoon or early evening so that guests can enjoy the beautiful sunset while they mingle. Also, make sure you have enough lighting if your party goes into the night.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>By following these tips and tricks, you’ll be well on your way to planning the perfect summer garden party. Remember, the most important thing is to have fun and enjoy spending time with friends and family in the great outdoors.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html">Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 5 Edible Flowers That You Can Grow In Your Garden This Summer</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/10/top-5-edible-flowers-that-you-can-grow-in-your-garden-this-summer/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/10/top-5-edible-flowers-that-you-can-grow-in-your-garden-this-summer/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 01:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=47</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Top 5 Edible Flowers That You Can Grow In Your Garden This Summer Summer is the perfect time to start growing edible flowers in your garden. Not only do they add beauty and color to your outdoor space, but they can also be used as a unique ingredient in your cooking. Here are the top [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/10/top-5-edible-flowers-that-you-can-grow-in-your-garden-this-summer/index.html">Top 5 Edible Flowers That You Can Grow In Your Garden This Summer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348b90_Top5EdibleFlowersThatYouCanGrowInYourGardenThisSummer.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Top 5 Edible Flowers That You Can Grow In Your Garden This Summer</h1>

<p>Summer is the perfect time to start growing edible flowers in your garden. Not only do they add beauty and color to your outdoor space, but they can also be used as a unique ingredient in your cooking. Here are the top 5 edible flowers that you can grow in your garden this summer:</p>

<h2>1. Nasturtiums</h2>
<p>Nasturtiums are a popular choice for adding color to salads or as a garnish on plates. They have a slightly peppery taste and come in shades of yellow, orange, and red.</p>

<h2>2. Calendula</h2>
<p>Calendula petals have a mild flavor that is often described as tangy or spicy. They can be used fresh or dried in teas, soups, stews, and even baked goods.</p>

<h2>3. Lavender</h2>
<p>Lavender is not only beautiful but also has a sweet floral flavor that works well in both sweet and savory dishes. It&#8217;s often used in desserts like lavender ice cream or paired with meats like lamb.</p>

<h2>4. Roses</h2>
<p>Roses come in an array of colors and flavors depending on the variety grown. The petals have a subtle fruity taste that pairs well with chocolate or can be used to create rose water for use in cocktails or baking.</p>

<h2>5. Borage</h2>
<p>Borage flowers have a mild cucumber-like flavor that makes them perfect for use in salads or as a garnish on chilled soups like gazpacho.</p>

<p>Growing these edible flowers is easy and requires minimal maintenance once established. Make sure to research each flower&#8217;s specific growing requirements before planting them into your garden. With a little bit of care and attention, you&#8217;ll have a beautiful and delicious addition to your summer meals.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/10/top-5-edible-flowers-that-you-can-grow-in-your-garden-this-summer/index.html">Top 5 Edible Flowers That You Can Grow In Your Garden This Summer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/10/top-5-edible-flowers-that-you-can-grow-in-your-garden-this-summer/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Have Fun With Kids This Summer by Starting A Family Vegetable Garden</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/08/have-fun-with-kids-this-summer-by-starting-a-family-vegetable-garden/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/08/have-fun-with-kids-this-summer-by-starting-a-family-vegetable-garden/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 15:16:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetable]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=33</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Have Fun With Kids This Summer by Starting A Family Vegetable Garden The summer season is here, and it&#8217;s a great time to get outside and enjoy the sunshine with your family. One way to have fun with your kids this summer is by starting a family vegetable garden. Not only will you be spending [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/08/have-fun-with-kids-this-summer-by-starting-a-family-vegetable-garden/index.html">Have Fun With Kids This Summer by Starting A Family Vegetable Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64347992_HaveFunWithKidsThisSummerByStartingAFamilyVegetableGarden.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Have Fun With Kids This Summer by Starting A Family Vegetable Garden</h1>

<p>The summer season is here, and it&#8217;s a great time to get outside and enjoy the sunshine with your family. One way to have fun with your kids this summer is by starting a family vegetable garden. Not only will you be spending quality time together, but you&#8217;ll also be teaching your children about where their food comes from and the importance of healthy eating habits.</p>

<h2>Choosing Your Garden Location</h2>

<p>The first step in starting a family vegetable garden is choosing the right location. Look for an area in your yard that gets plenty of sunlight and has good soil drainage. You&#8217;ll also want to make sure it&#8217;s easily accessible for both you and your kids.</p>

<h2>Selecting Vegetables to Grow</h2>

<p>Next, it&#8217;s time to decide which vegetables you want to grow in your garden. Some easy-to-grow options include tomatoes, cucumbers, carrots, lettuce, and peppers. You can also try growing herbs like basil or oregano.</p>

<h2>Gardening Supplies You Will Need</h2>

<p>To start your family vegetable garden, you will need some basic gardening supplies such as gardening gloves, hand trowel or shovel, watering can or hosepipe for watering plants regularly.</p>


<h2>Preparing Your Soil</h2>
 
<p>Before planting any seeds in the ground , prepare the soil by removing any weeds or debris that could hinder growth. Loosen up any compacted soil with a fork or hoe so that air can circulate better around plant roots.</p>


<h3>Planting Seeds or Seedlings </h3>
 
 <p>You can either buy seed packets from gardening stores or purchase pre-started seedlings from nurseries.Getting help from local nurseries may help know which are the best vegetables to grow in your area. </p>

<h2>Caring for Your Garden</h2>

<p>Once your garden is planted, it&#8217;s important to care for it properly. Make sure you water your plants regularly and fertilize them every few weeks. You&#8217;ll also want to keep an eye out for any pests or diseases that could harm your plants.</p>

<h3>The Fun Part: Harvesting Your Vegetables</h3>
 
 <p>Watching the plants grow can be so exciting, but nothing beats the feeling of harvesting fresh vegetables with your family! Encourage kids to help pick ripe vegetables from the garden and then use them in meals as a fun way to teach nutrition.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>Starting a family vegetable garden is a great way to spend quality time together while also teaching valuable life skills about food and healthy eating habits. With some basic gardening supplies, plenty of sunshine, and a little bit of patience, you&#8217;ll be harvesting fresh vegetables in no time!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/08/have-fun-with-kids-this-summer-by-starting-a-family-vegetable-garden/index.html">Have Fun With Kids This Summer by Starting A Family Vegetable Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/08/have-fun-with-kids-this-summer-by-starting-a-family-vegetable-garden/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 16:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-maintenance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perennials:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long Summer is a great time to enjoy your garden, but it can be challenging to keep plants looking healthy and blooming for the entire season. If you&#8217;re looking for easy-to-grow perennials that require minimal care and bloom all summer long, then you&#8217;ve come to the right place! Here [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html">Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643492fd_LowMaintenancePerennialsThatBloomAllSummerLong.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</h1>

<p>Summer is a great time to enjoy your garden, but it can be challenging to keep plants looking healthy and blooming for the entire season. If you&#8217;re looking for easy-to-grow perennials that require minimal care and bloom all summer long, then you&#8217;ve come to the right place! Here are some of our top picks:</p>

<h2>Lavender (Lavandula)</h2>
<p>Lavender is a fragrant perennial that produces beautiful purple flowers throughout the summer months. These plants prefer well-drained soil and full sun, making them perfect for dry gardens or rock gardens. Lavender requires minimal watering once established and can also be used in cooking or as dried flowers.</p>

<h2>Coneflower (Echinacea)</h2>
<p>Coneflowers are hardy perennials that produce daisy-like flowers in shades of pink, purple, and white. They thrive in full sun but can tolerate partial shade as well. Coneflowers are drought-tolerant and require very little maintenance once established. Deadheading spent blooms will encourage more flowering throughout the summer.</p>

<h2>Black-Eyed Susan (Rudbeckia)</h2>
<p>The bright yellow petals with brown centers make Black-eyed Susans stand out from other flowers in any garden bed they’re planted in. These heat-loving perennials are easy to grow and will flower throughout summer until fall arrives. They prefer full sun but can tolerate light shade.</p>

<h2>Daylily (Hemerocallis)</h2>
<p>The daylily is another tough perennial that can withstand extreme weather conditions while still blooming prolifically all summer long with little care required on your part. Daylilies come in many colors such as reds, oranges, yellows, pinks, and even some bi-colors. They prefer full sun but can tolerate partial shade.</p>

<h2>Salvia (Salvia)</h2>
<p>Salvias are a diverse group of perennials with many different species available in various colors such as blue, purple, pink and red. These plants thrive in well-drained soil and full sun to part shade but will tolerate dry conditions once established. Deadheading spent blooms will encourage more flowering throughout the summer.</p>

<h2>Sedum (Sedum)</h2>
<p>Sedums are succulent-like plants that come in many varieties and sizes. They have fleshy leaves and produce clusters of star-shaped flowers in shades of pink, red, yellow or white during the summer months. Sedums require little water or maintenance once established and thrive in hot sunny locations.</p>

<p>In conclusion, choosing low-maintenance perennials for your garden is a great way to enjoy beautiful blooms all summer long without having to put much effort into caring for them. When selecting your plants, make sure they&#8217;re appropriate for your growing zone, choose varieties that suit your style preferences and soil type.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/index.html">Low-Maintenance Perennials That Bloom All Summer Long</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/08/27/lowmaintenance-perennials-that-bloom-all-summer-long/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
