<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>perennial Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Creating a Low-Maintenance Perennial Garden</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/08/creating-a-lowmaintenance-perennial-garden/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/08/creating-a-lowmaintenance-perennial-garden/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 01:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[low-maintenance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perennial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Creating a Low-Maintenance Perennial Garden Gardening is a wonderful way to beautify your yard and enjoy the outdoors. However, it can also be a lot of work, particularly if you choose plants that require constant care and attention. If you want to create a garden that looks great year after year with minimal effort, consider [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/08/creating-a-lowmaintenance-perennial-garden/index.html">Creating a Low-Maintenance Perennial Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349335_CreatingALowMaintenancePerennialGarden.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Creating a Low-Maintenance Perennial Garden</h1>

<p>Gardening is a wonderful way to beautify your yard and enjoy the outdoors. However, it can also be a lot of work, particularly if you choose plants that require constant care and attention.</p>

<p>If you want to create a garden that looks great year after year with minimal effort, consider planting perennials. Perennials are plants that come back every year without needing to be replanted. They also tend to require less maintenance than annuals, which need to be planted fresh each spring.</p>

<h2>Choosing the Right Plants</h2>

<p>The key to creating a low-maintenance perennial garden is choosing the right plants for your climate and soil. Some popular low-maintenance perennials include:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Lavender:</strong> This fragrant herb thrives in hot, dry conditions and requires little water once established.</li>
  
  <li><strong>Sedum:</strong> Also known as stonecrop, this succulent plant comes in many varieties and colors and can tolerate drought conditions.</li>
  
  <li><strong>Coneflowers:</strong> These bright and cheerful flowers attract pollinators like bees and butterflies but are also tough enough to withstand heat waves.</li>
  
  <li><strong>Black-eyed Susans:</strong> Another pollinator favorite, these sunny yellow flowers bloom for weeks on end without needing much attention from you.</li>
  
  <li><strong>Hostas:</strong> These shade-loving plants come in many varieties with different leaf shapes and sizes. Once established, they require little watering or fertilizing.</li>
</ul>

<p>In addition to choosing the right plants for your garden&#8217;s growing conditions, consider planting them in groups according to their watering needs. This will make it easier for you to give each group the appropriate amount of water without over- or under-watering any individual plants.</p>

<h2>Preparing Your Soil</h2>

<p>Before you start planting, make sure your soil is in good condition. Perennials tend to do best in well-draining soil that&#8217;s rich in organic matter.</p>

<p>If your soil is heavy clay or sandy and doesn&#8217;t hold moisture well, amend it with compost or other organic matter to improve its texture and water-holding capacity. You can also add slow-release fertilizer pellets to give your perennials a nutrient boost as they grow.</p>

<h2>Maintenance Tips</h2>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve planted your low-maintenance perennial garden, there are a few things you can do to keep it looking great year after year:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Mulch:</strong> Adding a layer of mulch around your plants will help retain moisture in the soil and suppress weeds.</li>
  
  <li><strong>Deadhead:</strong> Removing spent flowers from your perennials encourages them to produce more blooms and keeps them looking neat and tidy.</li>
  
  <li><strong>Cut back:</strong> At the end of the growing season, cut back dead foliage and stems from your perennials so they&#8217;ll be ready to come back strong next year.</li>
  
  <li><strong>Fertilize:</strong> If your perennials seem lackluster or aren&#8217;t producing as many blooms as usual, consider giving them a dose of fertilizer to perk them up.</li>
</ul>

<p>A low-maintenance perennial garden is a beautiful way to enjoy nature without spending all your free time tending to it. By choosing the right plants for your growing conditions, preparing your soil properly, and following some basic maintenance tips, you can create a garden that will bring you joy for years to come.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/08/creating-a-lowmaintenance-perennial-garden/index.html">Creating a Low-Maintenance Perennial Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/08/creating-a-lowmaintenance-perennial-garden/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:39:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[every]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardener]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perennial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=88</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow Gardening is a wonderful hobby that can be relaxing and rewarding. One of the most popular types of plants to grow are perennials, which are plants that come back year after year. They require less work than annuals because they don&#8217;t need to be replanted every [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html">The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348f8a_TheTopPerennialFlowersEveryGardenerNeedsToGrow.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</h1>

<p>Gardening is a wonderful hobby that can be relaxing and rewarding. One of the most popular types of plants to grow are perennials, which are plants that come back year after year. They require less work than annuals because they don&#8217;t need to be replanted every year, making them perfect for busy gardeners who want beautiful blooms without all the maintenance.</p>

<h2>1. Black-eyed Susan</h2>
<p>Black-eyed Susans are one of the most popular perennial flowers and for good reason. These bright yellow flowers with dark centers add a pop of color to any garden or landscape. They bloom from midsummer through fall and attract butterflies and bees.</p>

<h2>2. Coneflowers</h2>
<p>Coneflowers come in a variety of colors including pink, purple, white and even green. They bloom from early summer through fall and are known for their distinctive cone-shaped center surrounded by petals. Coneflowers also attract birds and butterflies.</p>

<h2>3. Daylilies</h2>
<p>Daylilies have long been a favorite among gardeners due to their stunning blooms that last only one day but continue blooming throughout the summer months. They come in a wide variety of colors such as orange, yellow, red, pink, purple and even bi-colors.</p>

<h2>4. Peonies</h2>
<p>Peonies are beloved for their large fragrant blooms which range in color from white to red with many shades in between. These stunning flowers bloom in late spring to early summer and make excellent cut flowers.</p>

<h2>5. Salvia</h2>
<p>The tall spikes of salvia give height to any garden bed while attracting hummingbirds with their bright tubular blooms which come in shades of blue, purple, pink and red. They bloom from late spring through early fall.</p>

<h2>6. Sedum</h2>
<p>Sedum is a versatile perennial that comes in many shapes and sizes with blooms that range from white to pink to red. Sedums are known for their succulent foliage and ability to thrive in hot, dry conditions making them perfect for rock gardens or as ground cover.</p>

<h2>7. Russian Sage</h2>
<p>Russian sage has silvery-gray foliage which makes it an excellent backdrop for other plants in the garden. The tall spikes of small lavender-blue flowers add height and interest to any garden bed while attracting bees and butterflies.</p>

<h2>8. Hostas</h2>
<p>Hostas are prized for their lush foliage which ranges in color from deep green to blue-green to yellow-gold. They make excellent ground cover and work well as border plants due to their mounding habit.</p>

<h2>9. Bleeding Heart</h2>
<p>Bleeding heart is a classic cottage garden plant with beautiful heart-shaped flowers that dangle from delicate stems like jewelry on a necklace.Their blooms come in shades of pink, white or red and appear in early springtime before the weather gets too warm.</p>

<h2>10. Daffodils</h2>
<p>Daffodils are one of the earliest signs of spring with their bright yellow trumpet-shaped flowers.They&#8217;re easy-to-grow perennials that multiply over time so you&#8217;ll have more year after year!</p>

<p>No matter what your gardening style may be there&#8217;s sure to be a perennial flower out there waiting just for you! Happy planting!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/index.html">The Top Perennial Flowers Every Gardener Needs to Grow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/03/18/the-top-perennial-flowers-every-gardener-needs-to-grow/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
