<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>what, Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:48:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Composting 101: What, Why, and How?</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/11/27/composting-101-what-why-and-how/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/11/27/composting-101-what-why-and-how/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 17:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[composting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[what,]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=67</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Composting 101: What, Why, and How? Composting is a process of breaking down organic materials into nutrient-rich soil. It&#8217;s an excellent way to reduce waste and provide natural fertilizer for your garden. In this post, we&#8217;ll cover the basics of composting &#8211; what it is, why it&#8217;s important, and how to get started. What is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/11/27/composting-101-what-why-and-how/index.html">Composting 101: What, Why, and How?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348cbb_Composting101WhatWhyAndHow.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Composting 101: What, Why, and How?</h1>

<p>Composting is a process of breaking down organic materials into nutrient-rich soil. It&#8217;s an excellent way to reduce waste and provide natural fertilizer for your garden. In this post, we&#8217;ll cover the basics of composting &#8211; what it is, why it&#8217;s important, and how to get started.</p>

<h2>What is Composting?</h2>

<p>Composting is a natural process that occurs when microorganisms break down organic matter such as food scraps, yard waste, and paper products. The result is a rich soil amendment called compost that can be used in gardening or landscaping.</p>

<p>The key to successful composting lies in creating the right conditions for the microorganisms to thrive. This includes balancing carbon-rich materials (such as dried leaves) with nitrogen-rich materials (such as fruit and vegetable scraps), maintaining adequate moisture levels, and providing oxygen through regular turning or mixing.</p>

<h2>Why Compost?</h2>

<p>There are many reasons why composting is beneficial:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reduced Waste:</strong> By diverting organic material from landfills, you can significantly reduce your household waste.</li>
<li><strong>Natural Fertilizer:</strong> Compost provides essential nutrients for plants while improving soil structure and water retention.</li>
<li><strong>Cost Savings:</strong> Rather than purchasing expensive fertilizers or soil amendments, you can create your own using kitchen scraps and yard waste.</li>
<li><strong>Sustainable Living:</strong> Composting supports sustainable living by reducing greenhouse gas emissions associated with landfill disposal while also promoting healthy soils for future generations.</li>
</ul>

<h2>How to Start Composting</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;re ready to start composting at home, here are some simple steps to get started:</p>

<h3>Step 1: Choose a Composting Method</h3>
<p>There are several different methods for composting, including traditional bin systems, tumblers, and vermicomposting (using worms). Consider your space, time, and budget when selecting a method.</p>

<h3>Step 2: Gather Materials</h3>
<p>You&#8217;ll need a balance of carbon-rich &#8220;browns&#8221; and nitrogen-rich &#8220;greens.&#8221; Browns include dried leaves, straw, and paper products while greens include fruit/vegetable scraps and grass clippings. You can also add soil or finished compost to introduce microorganisms.</p>

<h3>Step 3: Build Your Pile or Bin</h3>
<p>If using a bin system, follow the manufacturer&#8217;s instructions. If creating an open pile in your yard, start with a layer of browns followed by greens. Continue layering until you have a pile that is roughly three feet tall.</p>

<h3>Step 4: Maintain Your Compost</h3>
<p>Aerate your compost regularly by turning or mixing it every few days. Keep it moist but not too wet &#8211; aim for the consistency of a wrung-out sponge. In 6-12 months (depending on conditions), you should have finished compost!</p>

<h2>The Bottom Line</h2>

<p>Composting is an easy way to reduce waste while creating natural fertilizer for your garden. By following these simple steps, you&#8217;ll be well on your way to successful composting!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/11/27/composting-101-what-why-and-how/index.html">Composting 101: What, Why, and How?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/11/27/composting-101-what-why-and-how/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
