<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>using Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/using/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/tag/using/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>DIY Projects Using Nature’s Bounty – Crafting With Items Found In Your Backyard or Local Farm Stand</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/11/diy-projects-using-natures-bounty-crafting-with-items-found-in-your-backyard-or-local-farm-stand/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/11/diy-projects-using-natures-bounty-crafting-with-items-found-in-your-backyard-or-local-farm-stand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 12:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bounty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crafting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[items]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature’s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[using]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>DIY Projects Using Nature’s Bounty – Crafting With Items Found In Your Backyard or Local Farm Stand If you&#8217;re looking for a fun and creative way to spend your free time, why not try some DIY projects using nature&#8217;s bounty? Not only is it a great way to get outside and enjoy the fresh air, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/11/diy-projects-using-natures-bounty-crafting-with-items-found-in-your-backyard-or-local-farm-stand/">DIY Projects Using Nature’s Bounty – Crafting With Items Found In Your Backyard or Local Farm Stand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349845_DiyProjectsUsingNatureSBountyCraftingWithItemsFoundInYourBackyardOrLocalFarmStand.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>DIY Projects Using Nature’s Bounty – Crafting With Items Found In Your Backyard or Local Farm Stand</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a fun and creative way to spend your free time, why not try some DIY projects using nature&#8217;s bounty? Not only is it a great way to get outside and enjoy the fresh air, but it&#8217;s also an opportunity to flex your crafting muscles and create something beautiful from items found right in your own backyard or local farm stand.</p>

<h2>Nature-Inspired Home Decor</h2>
<p>One of the best ways to incorporate nature into your home decor is by creating unique wall art. Collect leaves, flowers, and branches in different sizes and shapes. Arrange them on canvas board or paper in interesting patterns. Spray with a clear sealant for longevity.</p>
<p>You can also use wood slices as coasters, placemats or even as part of a wreath. Simply cut the wood into thin slices, sand them down until they are smooth, then decorate with paint or wood burning tools.</p>

<h2>Gardening Crafts</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re an avid gardener, there are many DIY projects that will allow you to showcase your green thumb while incorporating natural elements into your design. One idea is creating stone markers for plants. Simply collect stones from around your yard or nearby riverbeds and write the names of each plant on them using acrylic paint.</p>
<p>You can also make birdhouses out of gourds grown in your garden during the summer months. Once harvested and dried out completely indoors over winter (about 6 months), drill holes to hang string through at one end of each gourd; these become homes where birds can lay eggs come springtime!</p>


<h2>Natural Beauty Products </h2>
<p>Your backyard may be hiding some ingredients that could help you create your own natural beauty products. For example, you can make your own lip balm using beeswax and coconut oil. Simply melt the beeswax in a double boiler, add in coconut oil, and pour into small containers with lids. Once it cools down, you have a moisturizing lip balm that&#8217;s free of harmful chemicals.</p>
<p>You can also use herbs and flowers from your backyard to create homemade bath salts or oatmeal scrubs. Not only are these products more eco-friendly than store-bought alternatives, but they&#8217;re also gentle on your skin.</p>

<h2>Cooking With Fresh Ingredients</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re lucky enough to have a local farm stand nearby, why not take advantage of fresh ingredients for cooking? You can make your own jams and jellies using berries from the berry patch or apples from an orchard. You could also try making flavored oils by infusing olive oil with herbs such as rosemary or thyme found in your garden.</p>
<p>Another idea is to create homemade teas using dried herbs such as chamomile or peppermint grown right outside your home. Simply dry out the leaves and steep them in boiling water when ready to enjoy!</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>DIY projects using nature&#8217;s bounty are a great way to get creative while enjoying the outdoors at the same time. From creating unique home decor pieces to whipping up natural beauty products &#8211; there are so many possibilities! So next time you find yourself itching for a new project, look no further than your own backyard or local farm stand.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/11/diy-projects-using-natures-bounty-crafting-with-items-found-in-your-backyard-or-local-farm-stand/">DIY Projects Using Nature’s Bounty – Crafting With Items Found In Your Backyard or Local Farm Stand</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/12/11/diy-projects-using-natures-bounty-crafting-with-items-found-in-your-backyard-or-local-farm-stand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 23:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[improve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[using]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yield]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield Raised bed gardening is a popular method for growing plants, vegetables and fruits in a controlled environment. By raising the soil level above ground level, gardeners can create well-draining gardens that are easier to maintain and manage. These beds are perfect for those with poor quality [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/">Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349362_UsingRaisedBedsToImproveSoilQualityYield.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</h1>

<p>Raised bed gardening is a popular method for growing plants, vegetables and fruits in a controlled environment. By raising the soil level above ground level, gardeners can create well-draining gardens that are easier to maintain and manage. These beds are perfect for those with poor quality soil or who want to maximize their yield.</p>

<h2>What is a raised bed?</h2>

<p>A raised bed is essentially a large container made of wood, stone, brick or other materials that can hold soil. They come in all shapes and sizes but typically measure between 4 to 6 feet wide by 8 to 12 feet long. The height of the bed can vary depending on your preference but most range from 6 to 18 inches tall.</p>

<h2>The benefits of using raised beds</h2>

<p><strong>Better Soil Drainage:</strong> One of the biggest advantages of using raised beds is better drainage. When you raise the soil level above ground level you give excess water somewhere to go instead of sitting around your plant’s roots which can cause root rot and kill your plants off faster than anything else.</p>

<p><strong>Improved Soil Quality:</strong> Because you’re adding fresh soil into the bed, it’s easy for gardeners to amend their soil with compost, manure or other organic material without having to till up their entire yard. This means that over time, the nutrient density within these beds will be higher than natural soil allowing for better plant growth and stronger yields.</p>

<p><strong>Pest Control:</strong> Raised beds make it easier for gardeners to control pests like slugs and snails because they have less access points compared to traditional gardens where pests can crawl from any direction at any time.</p>

<p><strong>Easier Maintenance:</strong> With raised beds, you can easily manage the soil and plants without having to bend over which is great for gardeners with physical limitations or back problems. They also make it easier to plant and harvest as you don’t have to worry about stepping on your plants.</p>

<h2>How to build a raised bed</h2>

<p><strong>Step 1: Choose your location</strong></p>
<p>The first step in building a raised bed is choosing the right location. You’ll want an area that gets plenty of sunlight but also has access to water.</p>

<p><strong>Step 2: Gather Materials</strong></p>
<p>You’ll need wood (cedar, pine, or redwood are popular choices), screws, and tools like a drill and saw if you’re making them yourself. If you’re using stone or brick, be sure to gather enough materials before getting started.</p>

<p><strong>Step 3: Cut Wood To Size</strong></p>
<p>Cut your wood pieces down to size based on how large you want your raised bed to be. A typical size is 4 feet wide by 8 feet long but this can vary depending on your available space.</p>

<p><strong>Step 4: Assemble The Bed Frame</strong></p>
<p>To assemble the frame, screw together the sides at each corner until all four pieces are connected securely creating a box shape.

<p><strong>Step 5: Add Soil &#038; Compost Mixture</strong></p>
<p>Add good quality soil mixed with compost into the bed until its levelled off evenly.

<h2>In Conclusion,</h2>

Raised beds offer numerous benefits for gardeners looking for an easy way to grow their own food without having too much hassle in terms of maintenance or dealing with poor quality soil. Creating raised beds requires some effort upfront but once built they will last for years and provide the perfect environment for growing healthy plants.
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/">Using Raised Beds To Improve Soil Quality &#038; Yield</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/11/04/using-raised-beds-to-improve-soil-quality-yield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flower Arranging Techniques Using Freshly Cut Blooms from your Own Backyard</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/19/flower-arranging-techniques-using-freshly-cut-blooms-from-your-own-backyard/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/19/flower-arranging-techniques-using-freshly-cut-blooms-from-your-own-backyard/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 05:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arranging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blooms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[techniques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[using]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Flower Arranging Techniques Using Freshly Cut Blooms from your Own Backyard Flowers can bring life and beauty to any room. And what better way to decorate your home than using freshly cut blooms from your own backyard? Not only is it cost-effective, but it also adds a personal touch to your flower arrangements. Choosing the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/19/flower-arranging-techniques-using-freshly-cut-blooms-from-your-own-backyard/">Flower Arranging Techniques Using Freshly Cut Blooms from your Own Backyard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643498a8_FlowerArrangingTechniquesUsingFreshlyCutBloomsFromYourOwnBackyard.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Flower Arranging Techniques Using Freshly Cut Blooms from your Own Backyard</h1>

<p>Flowers can bring life and beauty to any room. And what better way to decorate your home than using freshly cut blooms from your own backyard? Not only is it cost-effective, but it also adds a personal touch to your flower arrangements.</p>

<h2>Choosing the Right Flowers</h2>

<p>The first step in flower arranging is choosing the right flowers. You want to select blooms that are fresh, healthy, and have sturdy stems. It&#8217;s best to pick flowers early in the morning or late in the evening when they are hydrated and cool.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re not sure which flowers to choose, consider creating a color scheme or theme for your arrangement. For example, if you want a vibrant summer bouquet, choose bright yellow sunflowers, orange marigolds, and purple asters.</p>

<h2>Cutting and Preparing Flowers</h2>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve selected your flowers, it&#8217;s time to cut them. Use sharp scissors or pruning shears to make clean cuts at an angle. Avoid tearing or crushing the stem as this can damage the flower&#8217;s ability to absorb water.</p>

<p>After cutting your flowers, remove any leaves or thorns that will be below the waterline in your vase. This will help prevent bacteria growth and keep your arrangement fresh for longer.</p>

<h2>Arranging Your Flowers</h2>

<p>Now comes the fun part – arranging your flowers! There are several techniques you can use depending on the style of arrangement you want:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Bouquet:</strong> A simple arrangement of mixed flowers with no particular shape or structure.</li>
  <li><strong>Oval:</strong> An elegant arrangement with taller stems in the center surrounded by shorter blooms around the edges.</li>
  <li><strong>Triangular:</strong> A balanced arrangement with focal flowers in the center and smaller blooms on either side.</li>
  <li><strong>Crescent:</strong> A unique arrangement where tall stems are arranged in a crescent shape with shorter blooms filling in the gaps.</li>
</ul>

<p>No matter which style you choose, start by placing your focal flowers in the center of your vase. Then add your filler flowers around the edges to create a balanced look. Finally, add any accents such as greenery or berries to fill in any gaps and add texture to your arrangement.</p>

<h2>Caring for Your Flowers</h2>

<p>To ensure that your flower arrangement lasts as long as possible, it&#8217;s important to care for them properly. Here are some tips:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Change the water every two days and re-cut the stems at an angle.</li>
  <li>Avoid placing your bouquet near direct sunlight or drafts that can dry out your flowers.</li>
  <li>If possible, keep your bouquet in a cool area overnight to prolong its freshness.</li>
</ul>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>Creating a beautiful flower arrangement doesn&#8217;t have to be complicated or expensive. By using freshly cut blooms from your own backyard and following these simple techniques, you can create stunning arrangements that will brighten up any space!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/19/flower-arranging-techniques-using-freshly-cut-blooms-from-your-own-backyard/">Flower Arranging Techniques Using Freshly Cut Blooms from your Own Backyard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/19/flower-arranging-techniques-using-freshly-cut-blooms-from-your-own-backyard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond Greenery: Using Edible Plants as Ornamentals</title>
		<link>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/06/beyond-greenery-using-edible-plants-as-ornamentals/</link>
					<comments>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/06/beyond-greenery-using-edible-plants-as-ornamentals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 20:57:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beyond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greenery:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ornamentals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[using]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/?p=28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Beyond Greenery: Using Edible Plants as Ornamentals When it comes to decorating our outdoor spaces, we often turn to traditional ornamental plants like roses, petunias and pansies. However, there is a growing trend towards using edible plants as ornamentals. Not only do they add visual interest to your yard or garden, but they also provide [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/06/beyond-greenery-using-edible-plants-as-ornamentals/">Beyond Greenery: Using Edible Plants as Ornamentals</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643478e7_BeyondGreeneryUsingEdiblePlantsAsOrnamentals.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Beyond Greenery: Using Edible Plants as Ornamentals</h1>

<p>When it comes to decorating our outdoor spaces, we often turn to traditional ornamental plants like roses, petunias and pansies. However, there is a growing trend towards using edible plants as ornamentals. Not only do they add visual interest to your yard or garden, but they also provide a source of fresh produce.</p>

<h2>The Benefits of Edible Ornamentals</h2>

<p>The use of edible plants in landscaping has numerous benefits beyond their aesthetic appeal:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Dual Purpose:</strong> By incorporating edible plants into your landscape design, you can enjoy both the beauty and taste of your garden.</li>

<li><strong>Sustainability:</strong> Growing your own food reduces your carbon footprint by reducing the need for transportation and packaging.</li>

<li><strong>Freshness:</strong> Nothing beats the taste of freshly picked produce right from your backyard. You&#8217;ll never have to worry about how long it&#8217;s been sitting on a grocery store shelf.</li>

<li><strong>Variety:</strong> The world of edibles offers endless variety so you can choose from fruits, vegetables and herbs that best suit your taste buds and climate zone.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Choosing the Right Edible Plants for Your Garden</h2>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in incorporating edible plants into your landscape design, there are some factors you should consider when selecting the right plant varieties for your space:</p>


<ul>
<li><strong>Climactic Conditions:</strong> Different plant varieties require different environmental conditions such as temperature range, humidity levels etc. For example, citrus trees thrive best in warm climates while strawberries do well in cooler regions with mild summers. </li>
  
<li><strong>Growth Habit &amp; Size :</strong> Consider how much space each plant requires as well as how tall it may grow. Avoid planting shrubs or trees too close to your home or other structures.</li>

<li><strong>Soil Type:</strong> Some plants require specific soil types in order to thrive, so make sure you know what kind of soil is available in your yard.

<li><strong>Pest Resistance:</strong> Certain plant species are more resistant to pests and diseases than others. Make sure the plants you choose are appropriate for your area and can fend off common pests without requiring excessive use of pesticides.

</ul>

<h2>Examples of Edible Ornamentals</h2>

<p>The following is a list of some popular edible plants that also add visual interest to any garden:</p>


<ul>
<li><strong>Lavender</strong>: In addition to its lovely purple flowers, lavender has fragrant leaves that can be used in cooking and baking.</li>

<li><strong>Sunflowers</strong>: Aside from their cheerful bright yellow heads, sunflower seeds can be roasted for a tasty snack.</li>

<li><strong>Rosemary</strong>: This herb not only adds flavor to dishes but also produces delicate blue flowers in the summer months.</li>

<li><strong>Tomatoes </strong>: While they do require support structures like cages or stakes, tomato plants produce both fruit and an attractive display of green foliage during growing season.</li>
  
<li><Strong>Espaliered Fruit Trees :</Strong >These specially-trained fruit trees grow flat against a wall or fence creating a beautiful living art piece while producing fresh fruits such as apples, pears and peaches. </li>
  
  <li><Strong>Swiss Chard :</Strong>This leafy vegetable comes in various shades such as white, red, pink with vibrant stalks which makes them visually appealing when grown together providing an array of color on your plate. </li>
  

</ul>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Using edible plants as ornamentals is a great way to create an attractive and practical garden space. By selecting the right varieties for your region, soil type, and climate zone, you can enjoy both the beauty and taste of your homegrown produce. So next time you&#8217;re planning a landscaping project consider adding some edible plants to the mix!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/06/beyond-greenery-using-edible-plants-as-ornamentals/">Beyond Greenery: Using Edible Plants as Ornamentals</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://gardening.toptiertalk.com/2022/01/06/beyond-greenery-using-edible-plants-as-ornamentals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
