<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>upcycling Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 08:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[household]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[items]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upcycling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=71</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters Do you have some old household items that you no longer use? Instead of throwing them away, why not upcycle them into unique planters for your home or garden? Not only is this a great way to repurpose items and reduce waste, but it can [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html">DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348d14_DiyIdeasForUpcyclingOldHouseholdItemsIntoUniquePlanters.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</h1>

<p>Do you have some old household items that you no longer use? Instead of throwing them away, why not upcycle them into unique planters for your home or garden? Not only is this a great way to repurpose items and reduce waste, but it can also add a fun and creative touch to your decor.</p>

<h2>Mason Jars</h2>
<p>Mason jars are versatile containers that can be easily transformed into charming planters. Simply fill the jar with soil and plant herbs, succulents or small flowers. You can also glue pebbles or moss onto the outside of the jar for added texture.</p>

<h2>Tin Cans</h2>
<p>Empty tin cans are another popular choice for DIY planters. To create a rustic look, wrap twine around the outside of the can and tie it in place. Then fill with soil and plants, making sure to punch drainage holes in the bottom first.</p>

<h2>Buckets And Pails</h2>
<p>If you have an old bucket or pail lying around, why not turn it into a planter? This works particularly well for larger plants such as tomatoes or peppers. You may need to drill drainage holes in the bottom of the container before adding soil and planting.</p>

<h2>Coffee Mugs</h2>
<p>You don&#8217;t need fancy ceramic pots to display your plants &#8211; coffee mugs work just fine! Choose brightly colored mugs for a playful touch or vintage cups for a more classic look.</p>

<h2>Suitcases And Briefcases</h2>
<p>For a truly unique planter idea, try using an old suitcase or briefcase as a container. These work well for larger plants such as ferns or ivies. Simply fill the case with soil and plants, then leave it open or prop it up to show off your greenery.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Upcycling old household items into planters is a fun and creative way to add some greenery to your home or garden. With just a little bit of creativity, you can turn almost anything into a unique planter that will be sure to impress your friends and family.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html">DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creative Ideas for Upcycling Old Pots and Containers in Your Garden</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/14/creative-ideas-for-upcycling-old-pots-and-containers-in-your-garden/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/10/14/creative-ideas-for-upcycling-old-pots-and-containers-in-your-garden/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 01:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[containers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upcycling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Creative Ideas for Upcycling Old Pots and Containers in Your Garden Do you have old pots and containers lying around the house? Don&#8217;t throw them away just yet! With a little creativity, you can upcycle these items and use them to add some character to your garden. Here are some ideas: 1. Turn old boots [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/14/creative-ideas-for-upcycling-old-pots-and-containers-in-your-garden/index.html">Creative Ideas for Upcycling Old Pots and Containers in Your Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/6434976d_CreativeIdeasForUpcyclingOldPotsAndContainersInYourGarden.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Creative Ideas for Upcycling Old Pots and Containers in Your Garden</h1>

<p>Do you have old pots and containers lying around the house? Don&#8217;t throw them away just yet! With a little creativity, you can upcycle these items and use them to add some character to your garden. Here are some ideas:</p>

<h2>1. Turn old boots into planters</h2>
<p>If you have an old pair of rain boots that are no longer being used, consider turning them into unique planters. Simply fill the boots with soil and add your favorite flowers or plants. You can place them on your front porch or along a walkway to add some color.</p>

<h2>2. Use tea cups as mini planters</h2>
<p>If you have mismatched tea cups lying around the house, don&#8217;t toss them out just yet! These make great mini planters for small succulents or herbs. Place them on a windowsill or create a small display on a shelf.</p>

<h2>3. Create vertical gardens with old pallets</h2>
<p>If you have access to old wooden pallets, consider using them to create a vertical garden. Simply attach terra cotta pots to the pallets using screws or nails, then hang the pallets vertically against a wall or fence.</p>

<h2>4. Turn colanders into hanging baskets</h2>
<p>If you have any old colanders that are no longer being used in the kitchen, turn them into unique hanging baskets for plants. Simply line the inside of the colander with moss or burlap fabric, then fill it with soil and add your favorite flowers.</p>

<h2>5. Use broken terracotta pots for fairy gardens</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever had a terracotta pot break on you, don&#8217;t toss it out just yet! Broken terracotta pots can be used to create unique fairy gardens. Simply arrange the broken pieces in a whimsical way, then add soil and miniature plants or fairy accessories.</p>

<h2>6. Turn old tires into raised garden beds</h2>
<p>If you have any old tires lying around, consider turning them into raised garden beds. Simply fill the tire with soil and compost, then plant your favorite vegetables or herbs.</p>

<h2>7. Use mason jars as candle holders</h2>
<p>If you have any old mason jars lying around, consider using them as unique candle holders for your outdoor space. Add sand or small pebbles to the bottom of the jar for stability, then place a tea light candle inside.</p>

<p>These are just a few ideas to get you started on upcycling old pots and containers in your garden. With a little creativity, you can turn these items into unique focal points that add character to your outdoor space.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/14/creative-ideas-for-upcycling-old-pots-and-containers-in-your-garden/index.html">Creative Ideas for Upcycling Old Pots and Containers in Your Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/10/14/creative-ideas-for-upcycling-old-pots-and-containers-in-your-garden/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
