<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>scratch Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tips for Starting a Vegetable Garden from Scratch</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/10/23/tips-for-starting-a-vegetable-garden-from-scratch/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/10/23/tips-for-starting-a-vegetable-garden-from-scratch/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 22:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scratch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetable]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=78</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tips for Starting a Vegetable Garden from Scratch Starting a vegetable garden from scratch can seem like a daunting task, but with the right knowledge and preparation, anyone can grow their own fresh produce. Whether you’re looking to save money on groceries, eat healthier, or just enjoy the satisfaction of growing your own food, here [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/23/tips-for-starting-a-vegetable-garden-from-scratch/index.html">Tips for Starting a Vegetable Garden from Scratch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348efd_TipsForStartingAVegetableGardenFromScratch.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Tips for Starting a Vegetable Garden from Scratch</h1>

<p>Starting a vegetable garden from scratch can seem like a daunting task, but with the right knowledge and preparation, anyone can grow their own fresh produce. Whether you’re looking to save money on groceries, eat healthier, or just enjoy the satisfaction of growing your own food, here are some tips to get started:</p>

<h2>Choose the Right Location</h2>

<p>The first step in starting a vegetable garden is choosing the right location. Look for an area that gets at least six hours of direct sunlight each day and has well-draining soil. Avoid areas with tree roots or other obstructions that may make it difficult to plant and tend to your garden.</p>

<h2>Start Small</h2>

<p>It’s easy to get carried away when planning your vegetable garden and end up with more than you can handle. Start small by planting just a few varieties of vegetables that you know you’ll use and enjoy. As you gain experience, you can always expand your garden.</p>

<h2>Prepare Your Soil</h2>

<p>The quality of your soil will have a big impact on the success of your vegetable garden. Before planting anything, test your soil pH and nutrient levels to determine if any amendments are needed. You may also want to consider adding compost or other organic matter to improve soil fertility and structure.</p>

<h2>Choose Your Vegetables Wisely</h2>

<p>Not all vegetables are created equal when it comes to growing conditions. Some require full sun while others prefer partial shade; some thrive in cool weather while others need heat to grow properly. Do some research on which vegetables will do best in your climate and growing conditions before making any purchases.</p>

<h2>Maintain Your Garden Regularly</h2>

<p>A successful vegetable garden requires regular maintenance throughout the growing season. This includes watering, weeding, fertilizing, and pest control. By staying on top of these tasks, you can help ensure a bountiful harvest.</p>

<h2>Harvest Your Vegetables at the Right Time</h2>

<p>Knowing when to harvest your vegetables is just as important as knowing how to grow them. Different vegetables have different harvesting requirements; some are best picked when they’re small and tender while others need to reach full maturity before they’re ready to eat. Learn about the specific needs of each vegetable in your garden to optimize your harvest.</p>

<p>Starting a vegetable garden from scratch may take some work, but the rewards are well worth it. With a little planning and preparation, anyone can enjoy the satisfaction of growing their own fresh produce.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/10/23/tips-for-starting-a-vegetable-garden-from-scratch/index.html">Tips for Starting a Vegetable Garden from Scratch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/10/23/tips-for-starting-a-vegetable-garden-from-scratch/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Start your Own Herb Garden from Scratch</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/01/13/how-to-start-your-own-herb-garden-from-scratch/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/01/13/how-to-start-your-own-herb-garden-from-scratch/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 08:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scratch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[start]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=79</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>How to Start your Own Herb Garden from Scratch If you are looking for a fun and rewarding hobby that can also provide you with fresh herbs for cooking, consider starting your own herb garden! With some basic knowledge and a little bit of effort, you can create a thriving garden filled with aromatic and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/01/13/how-to-start-your-own-herb-garden-from-scratch/index.html">How to Start your Own Herb Garden from Scratch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348efd_HowToStartYourOwnHerbGardenFromScratch.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>How to Start your Own Herb Garden from Scratch</h1>

<p>If you are looking for a fun and rewarding hobby that can also provide you with fresh herbs for cooking, consider starting your own herb garden! With some basic knowledge and a little bit of effort, you can create a thriving garden filled with aromatic and flavorful herbs.</p>

<h2>Step 1: Choose your Herbs</h2>

<p>The first step in starting an herb garden is deciding which herbs you want to grow. Consider the types of dishes you like to cook and which herbs would complement them best. Some popular options include basil, rosemary, thyme, oregano, parsley, cilantro, and mint. You can either purchase seeds or starter plants at a nursery or online retailer.</p>

<h2>Step 2: Find the Right Location</h2>

<p>In order for your herb garden to thrive, it needs plenty of sunlight. Look for a location that gets at least six hours of direct sunlight each day. If possible, choose a spot near your kitchen so that you can easily access the herbs while cooking.</p>

<h2>Step 3: Prepare the Soil</h2>

<p>The quality of soil is crucial when growing any type of plant. For an herb garden, use well-draining soil with plenty of organic matter such as compost or aged manure mixed in. This will help provide nutrients and retain moisture for healthy plant growth.</p>

<h2>Step 4: Plant Your Herbs</h2>

<p>When planting your herbs, space them out according to their recommended distance apart based on their mature size. Dig holes slightly larger than the root ball and gently loosen any tangled roots before placing them in the ground. Cover with soil up to the base of the stem.</p>

<h2>Step 5: Water Regularly</h2>

<p>Herbs need consistent moisture to grow, so make sure to water them regularly. However, be careful not to overwater as this can lead to root rot. A good rule of thumb is to stick your finger into the soil up to the first knuckle and water when it feels dry at that depth.</p>

<h2>Step 6: Fertilize</h2>

<p>To encourage healthy growth and strong flavor, fertilize your herb garden with a balanced fertilizer once every two weeks during the growing season (spring through fall).</p>

<h2>Step 7: Harvest Your Herbs</h2>

<p>Once your herbs have reached a mature size, you can begin harvesting them for use in cooking. Be sure to only remove about one-third of the plant at a time so that it has enough foliage left to continue growing.</p>

<p>Congratulations! You now know how to start your own herb garden from scratch. With some patience and care, you&#8217;ll soon have a thriving herb garden that will provide you with fresh herbs for all of your culinary creations.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/01/13/how-to-start-your-own-herb-garden-from-scratch/index.html">How to Start your Own Herb Garden from Scratch</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/01/13/how-to-start-your-own-herb-garden-from-scratch/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
