<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>planning Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 11:40:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hostess]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess Summer is here and it’s time to take advantage of the beautiful weather by hosting a garden party! Whether you’re planning a small get-together or a big celebration, there are some key tips and tricks to keep in mind that will [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html">Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/6434982e_PlanningThePerfectSummerGardenPartyTipsTricksFromAnExpertHostess.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</h1>

<p>Summer is here and it’s time to take advantage of the beautiful weather by hosting a garden party! Whether you’re planning a small get-together or a big celebration, there are some key tips and tricks to keep in mind that will make your party a success.</p>

<h2>Location</h2>
<p>The first step in planning your garden party is choosing the perfect location. If you have a backyard or garden, that’s an obvious choice, but don’t be afraid to think outside the box. You could also consider hosting your party at a local park or beach if they allow gatherings. Whatever location you choose, make sure it has enough space for guests and any activities you have planned.</p>

<h2>Decorations</h2>
<p>No party is complete without decorations! For a garden party, embrace nature by incorporating floral arrangements and greenery into your decor. You could even create centerpieces using flowers and plants from your own garden. String lights are also a great way to add ambiance once the sun goes down.</p>

<h2>Food &#038; Drinks</h2>
<p>A summer garden party calls for light and refreshing food and drinks. Consider serving finger foods such as fruit skewers, bruschetta, or mini quiches. For drinks, offer lemonade or iced tea as non-alcoholic options and provide beer or wine for those who want something stronger.</p>

<h2>Activities</h2>
<p>No one wants to attend a boring party! Plan some activities to keep your guests entertained throughout the event. Lawn games such as bocce ball or croquet are always crowd-pleasers. You could also set up a photo booth area with props for guests to take memorable photos together.</p>

<h2>Timing</h2>
<p>Timing is key when it comes to hosting a garden party. Plan your party for late afternoon or early evening so that guests can enjoy the beautiful sunset while they mingle. Also, make sure you have enough lighting if your party goes into the night.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>By following these tips and tricks, you’ll be well on your way to planning the perfect summer garden party. Remember, the most important thing is to have fun and enjoy spending time with friends and family in the great outdoors.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/index.html">Planning the Perfect Summer Garden Party – Tips &#038; Tricks from an Expert Hostess</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/12/17/planning-the-perfect-summer-garden-party-tips-tricks-from-an-expert-hostess/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 16:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather Fall is the perfect time to start planning your garden for the upcoming season. Cooler weather and shorter days make it an ideal time to grow vegetables that thrive in these conditions. Here are some great options to consider: Kale Kale is a hardy vegetable [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html">Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349413_PlanningYourFallHarvestWithVegetablesThatLoveCoolerWeather.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</h1>

<p>Fall is the perfect time to start planning your garden for the upcoming season. Cooler weather and shorter days make it an ideal time to grow vegetables that thrive in these conditions. Here are some great options to consider:</p>

<h2>Kale</h2>
<p>Kale is a hardy vegetable that can withstand cooler temperatures, making it a great choice for fall gardening. It&#8217;s also packed with nutrients like vitamin C, vitamin K, and beta carotene. Kale can be grown from seeds or transplants and will continue to produce leaves throughout the season.</p>

<h2>Spinach</h2>
<p>Another leafy green that loves cooler weather is spinach. Rich in iron and other essential vitamins, spinach is easy to grow from seed or transplants. Plant it early enough in the fall so that it has time to mature before winter arrives.</p>

<h2>Carrots</h2>
<p>Carrots are a root vegetable that love cooler weather, making them perfect for fall gardens. They&#8217;re packed with vitamins A and C and are easy to grow from seed. Just make sure they have plenty of space to grow deep into the soil.</p>

<h2>Broccoli</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a hearty vegetable that loves cooler weather, broccoli is an excellent choice. It&#8217;s high in fiber, vitamin C, and other nutrients making it a healthy addition to any meal plan. Broccoli grows best from seeds planted directly in the ground.</p>

<h2>Cauliflower</h2>
<p>Cauliflower is another cool-weather crop that&#8217;s packed with vitamins and minerals like vitamin C, folate, and potassium. It can be grown from seeds or transplants but needs plenty of space between plants as they can get quite large.</p>

<h2>Brussels Sprouts</h2>
<p>Brussels sprouts are a member of the cabbage family and love cooler weather. They&#8217;re packed with vitamin C, folate, and fiber, making them a healthy choice for any meal plan. Plant them in early fall so they have time to mature before winter arrives.</p>

<h2>Cabbage</h2>
<p>Cabbage is another member of the brassica family that thrives in cooler weather. It&#8217;s high in vitamin C and can be grown from seeds or transplants. Make sure it has plenty of space between plants as cabbage can get quite large.</p>

<p>When planning your fall harvest garden, make sure to choose vegetables that love cooler weather like kale, spinach, carrots, broccoli, cauliflower, Brussels sprouts, and cabbage. These veggies are packed with nutrients and will keep you well-fed throughout the fall season.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html">Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Avoid These Common Mistakes When Planning Your Spring Garden</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/08/26/avoid-these-common-mistakes-when-planning-your-spring-garden/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/08/26/avoid-these-common-mistakes-when-planning-your-spring-garden/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avoid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[common]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mistakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[these]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Avoid These Common Mistakes When Planning Your Spring Garden Spring is just around the corner, and it&#8217;s time to start thinking about your garden. Whether you&#8217;re an experienced gardener or a beginner, planning your spring garden can be both exciting and overwhelming. To help you get started on the right foot, we&#8217;ve put together a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/26/avoid-these-common-mistakes-when-planning-your-spring-garden/index.html">Avoid These Common Mistakes When Planning Your Spring Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349043_AvoidTheseCommonMistakesWhenPlanningYourSpringGarden.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Avoid These Common Mistakes When Planning Your Spring Garden</h1>

<p>Spring is just around the corner, and it&#8217;s time to start thinking about your garden. Whether you&#8217;re an experienced gardener or a beginner, planning your spring garden can be both exciting and overwhelming. To help you get started on the right foot, we&#8217;ve put together a list of common mistakes to avoid.</p>

<h2>Mistake #1: Not Considering Your Climate Zone</h2>

<p>When planning your spring garden, it&#8217;s important to consider your climate zone. Different plants thrive in different climates, so make sure you choose plants that are suitable for your area. You can check your climate zone online or ask at your local nursery.</p>

<h2>Mistake #2: Overcrowding Your Garden</h2>

<p>It can be tempting to pack as many plants as possible into your garden, but overcrowding can actually harm your plants. Overcrowding leads to poor air circulation and increased moisture levels which can lead to diseases and pests. Make sure to give each plant enough space according to its needs.</p>

<h2>Mistake #3: Neglecting Soil Preparation</h2>

<p>The soil is the foundation of any healthy garden, so neglecting soil preparation is a big mistake. Before planting anything in the spring, take the time to prepare your soil by adding organic matter such as compost or manure. This will provide essential nutrients for your plants and improve soil structure.</p>

<h2>Mistake #4: Forgetting About Watering Needs</h2>

<p>Watering is critical for maintaining a healthy garden, but forgetting about watering needs is another common mistake. Make sure you know how much water each plant requires and adjust accordingly based on rainfall amounts and weather conditions.</p>

<h2>Mistake #5: Planting Invasive Species</h2>

<p>Planting invasive species can be a costly mistake. Invasive plants not only take over your garden but also harm local ecosystems by outcompeting native species. Before planting anything new, make sure to research its growth habits and potential invasiveness.</p>

<h2>Mistake #6: Ignoring Pest Control</h2>

<p>Pest control is an important part of maintaining a healthy garden. Ignoring pest control can lead to significant plant damage or even complete loss of crops. Research different pest control methods and choose one that works for you.</p>

<h2>Mistake #7: Not Planning for Succession Planting</h2>

<p>Succession planting involves planting crops in succession so that you have a continuous harvest throughout the growing season. Not planning for succession planting can result in a glut of produce all at once followed by nothing later on. Make sure to plan ahead to ensure a steady supply of fresh vegetables and fruits.</p>

<h2>Mistake #8: Failing to Rotate Crops</h2>

<p>Rotating crops is essential for preventing soil-borne diseases and pests from building up in the soil over time. Failing to rotate crops means that your plants will be more susceptible to disease, leading to poor yields or complete crop failure.</p>

<p>Avoiding these common mistakes will help you create a thriving spring garden that brings joy and beauty throughout the growing season.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/26/avoid-these-common-mistakes-when-planning-your-spring-garden/index.html">Avoid These Common Mistakes When Planning Your Spring Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/08/26/avoid-these-common-mistakes-when-planning-your-spring-garden/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
