<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>balcony Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Balcony Gardens – Making Green Spaces out of Small Spaces</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/08/17/balcony-gardens-making-green-spaces-out-of-small-spaces/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/08/17/balcony-gardens-making-green-spaces-out-of-small-spaces/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 13:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balcony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Balcony Gardens – Making Green Spaces out of Small Spaces Living in an apartment or a small house doesn&#8217;t mean giving up on having a garden. In fact, with the right approach and some creativity, you can transform your small balcony into a green oasis. Balcony gardens are becoming increasingly popular among urban dwellers who [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/17/balcony-gardens-making-green-spaces-out-of-small-spaces/index.html">Balcony Gardens – Making Green Spaces out of Small Spaces</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643493b8_BalconyGardensMakingGreenSpacesOutOfSmallSpaces.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Balcony Gardens – Making Green Spaces out of Small Spaces</h1>

<p>Living in an apartment or a small house doesn&#8217;t mean giving up on having a garden. In fact, with the right approach and some creativity, you can transform your small balcony into a green oasis. Balcony gardens are becoming increasingly popular among urban dwellers who want to bring nature closer to their homes.</p>

<h2>Choose the Right Plants</h2>

<p>The first step towards creating a balcony garden is choosing the right plants. Since balconies usually have limited space, it&#8217;s essential to select plants that will thrive in small containers. Some good options include herbs like basil, rosemary, and thyme, as well as flowers such as petunias, marigolds, and pansies.</p>

<p>You should also consider the amount of sunlight your balcony receives. If it&#8217;s mostly shaded, ferns and ivies are great choices. On the other hand, if it gets direct sunlight for most of the day, succulents like cacti and jade plants are ideal.</p>

<h2>Pick the Right Containers</h2>

<p>The container you choose for your plants is just as important as selecting the right ones. You want something that is sturdy enough to hold soil but not so heavy that it makes your balcony feel cluttered.</p>

<p>One option is hanging baskets that allow you to grow trailing plants such as ivy or geraniums without taking up valuable floor space. Another option is vertical planters that attach to walls or railings and can hold several different types of plants at once.</p>

<h2>Create a Cohesive Design</h2>

<p>A well-designed balcony garden should feel cohesive and put together rather than cluttered or haphazardly arranged. Start by choosing a color scheme for your pots and furniture – neutrals like black, white, and grey are always a safe bet, but you could also opt for bold colors that complement your plants.</p>

<p>You can also create levels by using different-sized pots or stands to add visual interest. A small bistro table and chairs can provide a cozy spot to enjoy your new green space.</p>

<h2>Maintain Your Garden</h2>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve created your balcony garden, it&#8217;s essential to maintain it properly. This means watering your plants regularly and fertilizing them as needed. You should also be mindful of pests like spider mites or aphids that can quickly spread from one plant to another.</p>

<p>Deadheading – removing dead flowers – is an essential part of maintaining the health of your garden. It encourages more blooms and prevents disease from spreading.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>A balcony garden is an excellent way to bring nature into your home and create a peaceful retreat in the middle of the city. With some careful planning, appropriate plant selection, and creative use of containers, anyone can transform their small outdoor space into a lush oasis.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/08/17/balcony-gardens-making-green-spaces-out-of-small-spaces/index.html">Balcony Gardens – Making Green Spaces out of Small Spaces</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/08/17/balcony-gardens-making-green-spaces-out-of-small-spaces/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
