<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>unconventional Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Unconventional Veggies to Grow in your Home Garden</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/01/30/unconventional-veggies-to-grow-in-your-home-garden/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/01/30/unconventional-veggies-to-grow-in-your-home-garden/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 20:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unconventional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veggies]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=63</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Unconventional Veggies to Grow in your Home Garden If you&#8217;re a fan of gardening and growing your own fruits and vegetables, why not try something new this year? Sure, you can always grow the classics like tomatoes, carrots, and cucumbers, but why not add some variety to your harvest? Here are some unconventional veggies that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/01/30/unconventional-veggies-to-grow-in-your-home-garden/index.html">Unconventional Veggies to Grow in your Home Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348c7a_UnconventionalVeggiesToGrowInYourHomeGarden.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Unconventional Veggies to Grow in your Home Garden</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re a fan of gardening and growing your own fruits and vegetables, why not try something new this year? Sure, you can always grow the classics like tomatoes, carrots, and cucumbers, but why not add some variety to your harvest? Here are some unconventional veggies that you can easily grow in your home garden.</p>

<h2>Kohlrabi</h2>
<p>Kohlrabi is a unique member of the cabbage family that has a slightly sweet taste with a hint of spiciness. It&#8217;s rich in vitamins C and K, as well as potassium. To grow kohlrabi, you&#8217;ll need to start by planting seeds indoors about six weeks before the last frost date. Once the seedlings have sprouted and grown their first true leaves, they can be transplanted into your garden. Kohlrabi grows best in cool weather conditions and takes about 55-60 days to mature.</p>

<h2>Chinese Eggplant</h2>
<p>Chinese eggplants are long and thin compared to their more common globe-shaped counterparts. They have a mild flavor that works well in stir-fries or roasted dishes. Chinese eggplants require warm soil temperatures to germinate so make sure you wait until after the last frost date before sowing seeds directly into your garden. The plants will need support as they grow since they tend to be top-heavy when laden with fruit.</p>

<h2>Bitter Melon</h2>
<p>Bitter melon is a gourd-like vegetable popular in Asian cuisine known for its bitterness which fades away once it&#8217;s cooked with spices or other ingredients. It&#8217;s packed with vitamin C, fiber, iron, magnesium and potassium making it an excellent addition to any diet. Bitter melons need warm soil temperatures above 70°F (21°C) to germinate, so it&#8217;s best to start seeds indoors and transplant the seedlings once they&#8217;re strong enough.</p>

<h2>Malabar Spinach</h2>
<p>If you love spinach but hate how quickly it bolts in the heat, consider growing Malabar spinach instead. This leafy green is actually a vine that grows up trellises or fences. It has a mild flavor and is perfect for using in salads or as a cooked green. Malabar spinach loves hot weather and can be grown throughout the summer months.</p>

<h2>Celeriac</h2>
<p>Celeriac, also known as celery root, is a root vegetable with a slightly nutty taste similar to celery. It&#8217;s high in fiber, antioxidants, vitamins C and K as well as phosphorus making it an excellent addition to soups, stews or roasted dishes. To grow celeriac, start by planting seeds indoors about 10-12 weeks before your last frost date since it takes longer than most other vegetables to mature.</p>

<p>These are just some of the unconventional veggies you can grow in your home garden this year. Don&#8217;t be afraid to try something new &#8211; you may discover a new favorite vegetable!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/01/30/unconventional-veggies-to-grow-in-your-home-garden/index.html">Unconventional Veggies to Grow in your Home Garden</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/01/30/unconventional-veggies-to-grow-in-your-home-garden/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
