<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>regrowing Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Steps for Regrowing Vegetables from Scraps</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/04/15/steps-for-regrowing-vegetables-from-scraps/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/04/15/steps-for-regrowing-vegetables-from-scraps/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 05:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regrowing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scraps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetables]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Steps for Regrowing Vegetables from Scraps Do you often find yourself throwing away vegetable scraps, such as the bottoms of lettuce heads or the ends of celery stalks? Did you know that these scraps can actually be regrown into new vegetables? Not only is this a great way to reduce food waste, but it can [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/15/steps-for-regrowing-vegetables-from-scraps/index.html">Steps for Regrowing Vegetables from Scraps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/6434939f_StepsForRegrowingVegetablesFromScraps.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Steps for Regrowing Vegetables from Scraps</h1>

<p>Do you often find yourself throwing away vegetable scraps, such as the bottoms of lettuce heads or the ends of celery stalks? Did you know that these scraps can actually be regrown into new vegetables? Not only is this a great way to reduce food waste, but it can also save you money on groceries. Here are some simple steps for regrowing vegetables from scraps:</p>

<h2>Lettuce and Cabbage</h2>
<p>To regrow lettuce or cabbage, simply cut off the bottom inch of the head and place it in a bowl with about half an inch of water. Place the bowl in a sunny spot and change the water every couple of days. After about a week, you should start to see new leaves sprouting from the center of the plant. Once these leaves are a few inches tall, you can transplant them into soil.</p>

<h2>Celery</h2>
<p>To regrow celery, cut off the bottom two inches of the stalk and place it in a shallow dish with enough water to cover about half an inch of the bottom. Place the dish in a sunny spot and change out the water every couple of days. After about a week, small leaves will begin to emerge from inside the base. Once these leaves are at least three inches long, you can transplant them into soil.</p>

<h2>Carrots</h2>
<p>To regrow carrots, take leftover carrot tops (the greens) and place them in a shallow dish with water. Change out their water every day until they grow roots which should take around 4-5 days then transfer them over to soil.</p>

<h2>Scallions</h2>
<p>To regrow scallions (also known as green onions), simply save their white bulbs after chopping up their green stems. Place the bulbs in a glass filled with water so that the roots are submerged, and change out their water every couple of days. You should see new green shoots emerging from the top within a week or two.</p>

<h2>Bok Choy</h2>
<p>Bok choy is also an easy vegetable to regrow. Simply cut off the bottom inch of the head and place it in a shallow dish with enough water to cover about half an inch of the bottom. Keep changing their water every 1-2 days until you see new leaves sprouting up then transfer them over to soil.</p>

<p>Regrowing vegetables from scraps is not only fun but also helps reduce food waste while allowing you to enjoy fresh produce at home without spending money on buying new seeds or plants. So next time you&#8217;re cooking and have some leftover vegetable scraps, give these steps a try!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/04/15/steps-for-regrowing-vegetables-from-scraps/index.html">Steps for Regrowing Vegetables from Scraps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/04/15/steps-for-regrowing-vegetables-from-scraps/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
