<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>landscape Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 10:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[designing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[works]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You If you&#8217;re interested in growing your own food, but don&#8217;t have the space or time for a traditional vegetable garden, edible landscaping may be the perfect solution for you. Edible landscaping combines both ornamental and edible plants to create a beautiful and functional landscape that can provide [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html">Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643493f7_DesigningAnEdibleLandscapeThatWorksForYou.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in growing your own food, but don&#8217;t have the space or time for a traditional vegetable garden, edible landscaping may be the perfect solution for you. Edible landscaping combines both ornamental and edible plants to create a beautiful and functional landscape that can provide fresh fruits, vegetables, and herbs.</p>

<h2>Benefits of Edible Landscaping</h2>

<p>There are many benefits to designing an edible landscape:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Increased access to fresh, healthy produce</li>
  <li>Aesthetic appeal of combining ornamental and edible plants</li>
  <li>Better utilization of outdoor spaces</li>
  <li>Increase biodiversity in your yard by attracting pollinators and other beneficial insects </li>
  <li>Saves money on groceries </li>
  <li>You can control what chemicals and fertilizers are used (if any) when growing your own produce </li>
</ul>

<h2>Planning Your Edible Landscape Design</h2>

<p>The first step in designing your edible landscape is to evaluate your space. Consider things like sunlight exposure, soil type, drainage, and existing plant life. Take measurements of the area so you can plan accordingly.</p>

<p>Next, decide which edibles you want to include in your design. Think about what types of fruits, vegetables or herbs you enjoy eating – this will make it more likely that you&#8217;ll maintain them throughout the season. Here are some popular options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Fruits: strawberries, blueberries, raspberries or dwarf fruit trees such as peach or apple trees </li>
  <li>Veggies: tomatoes, peppers or spinach </lil
  <lil>Herbs: thyme rosemary basil mint oregano</li>
</ul>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve decided what you want to grow, consider how each plant will fit into your landscape design. Think about the color, texture and shape of both ornamental and edible plants. Consider adding raised beds or containers for a more organized look.</p>

<h2>Maintaining Your Edible Landscape</h2>

<p>The key to maintaining an edible landscape is regular maintenance. This includes watering, pruning, fertilizing and pest control. Make sure to keep up with these tasks so that your plants stay healthy and strong. </p>

<p>Also be sure to harvest produce regularly – this will help prevent any waste or spoilage, as well as encourage continued growth throughout the season.</p>

<h2>In Conclusion</h2>

<p>An edible landscape can be a beautiful addition to any outdoor space while providing fresh fruits, vegetables and herbs for your family to enjoy. With careful planning and regular maintenance, you can create a functional garden that&#8217;s both aesthetically pleasing and practical.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/index.html">Designing an Edible Landscape that Works for You</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/24/designing-an-edible-landscape-that-works-for-you/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Lawn To Landscape: Transforming Your Yard Into a Beautiful Oasis</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/21/from-lawn-to-landscape-transforming-your-yard-into-a-beautiful-oasis/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/21/from-lawn-to-landscape-transforming-your-yard-into-a-beautiful-oasis/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 15:27:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beautiful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oasis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transforming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>From Lawn To Landscape: Transforming Your Yard Into a Beautiful Oasis Do you look out at your yard and see nothing but a plain, boring lawn? If so, it&#8217;s time to transform your yard into a beautiful oasis! With a little planning, hard work, and creativity, you can turn your yard into an outdoor paradise. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/21/from-lawn-to-landscape-transforming-your-yard-into-a-beautiful-oasis/index.html">From Lawn To Landscape: Transforming Your Yard Into a Beautiful Oasis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349791_FromLawnToLandscapeTransformingYourYardIntoABeautifulOasis.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>From Lawn To Landscape: Transforming Your Yard Into a Beautiful Oasis</h1>

<p>Do you look out at your yard and see nothing but a plain, boring lawn? If so, it&#8217;s time to transform your yard into a beautiful oasis! With a little planning, hard work, and creativity, you can turn your yard into an outdoor paradise.</p>

<h2>Assess Your Space</h2>

<p>The first step in transforming your yard is to assess the space you have to work with. Take note of any existing trees or features that you want to keep. Consider how much sun exposure different areas of your yard get throughout the day. This will help you determine which plants will thrive in each area.</p>

<h2>Create A Plan</h2>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve assessed your space, it&#8217;s time to create a plan for your new landscape. Think about what type of garden style appeals to you &#8211; do you prefer modern and minimalistic, or lush and tropical? Make sure that your plan includes both hardscape elements (like walkways and patios) as well as softscape elements (like plants).</p>

<h2>Add Hardscaping Elements</h2>

<p>Hardscaping elements are the non-plant features that make up your landscape design. These can include things like patios, walkways, retaining walls, and even water features like fountains or ponds. When adding hardscaping elements to your yard, consider both form and function &#8211; not only should they look great but they should also serve a practical purpose.</p>

<h2>Select The Right Plants</h2>

<p>The right plants are essential for creating the perfect landscape design. When selecting plants for your new garden bed or outdoor space consider factors such as color scheme, texture variation and height difference between plants. It’s important that each plant has enough room for growth, receives the right amount of sunlight and water, and is suitable for your climate.</p>

<h2>Add Lighting</h2>

<p>Outdoor lighting not only enhances the beauty of your landscape but also provides safety and security. Consider adding ambient lighting to highlight key features such as trees or architectural elements. You can also add task lighting to illuminate walkways or patio areas. Solar powered lights are a great option if you want an eco-friendly option that doesn’t require wiring.</p>

<h2>Maintain Your Landscape</h2>

<p>Once you&#8217;ve transformed your yard into a beautiful oasis, it&#8217;s important to maintain it regularly. This includes watering plants as needed, pruning trees and shrubs, fertilizing soil when required, cleaning up dead leaves debris and mowing lawn grasses. Regular maintenance will ensure that your new landscape stays healthy and vibrant for years to come.</p>

<h2>The Final Word</h2>

<p>Transforming your yard from a plain lawn into a beautiful oasis takes time and effort but it’s worth it in the end! With careful planning, thoughtful design choices, appropriate plant selection and ongoing maintenance you can create an outdoor space that’s not only visually appealing but functional too.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/21/from-lawn-to-landscape-transforming-your-yard-into-a-beautiful-oasis/index.html">From Lawn To Landscape: Transforming Your Yard Into a Beautiful Oasis</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/21/from-lawn-to-landscape-transforming-your-yard-into-a-beautiful-oasis/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Tips for Creating a Stunning Garden Landscape</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/07/14/10-tips-for-creating-a-stunning-garden-landscape/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/07/14/10-tips-for-creating-a-stunning-garden-landscape/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 08:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stunning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=15</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>10 Tips for Creating a Stunning Garden Landscape Gardening is a wonderful hobby that can provide numerous benefits such as stress relief, fresh air, and exercise. However, creating a stunning garden landscape requires careful planning and hard work. In this blog post, we will share 10 tips to help you create the garden of your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/07/14/10-tips-for-creating-a-stunning-garden-landscape/index.html">10 Tips for Creating a Stunning Garden Landscape</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64347736_10TipsForCreatingAStunningGardenLandscape.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>10 Tips for Creating a Stunning Garden Landscape</h1>

<p>Gardening is a wonderful hobby that can provide numerous benefits such as stress relief, fresh air, and exercise. However, creating a stunning garden landscape requires careful planning and hard work. In this blog post, we will share 10 tips to help you create the garden of your dreams.</p>

<h2>1. Understand Your Soil Type</h2>
<p>The first step in creating a beautiful garden is to understand your soil type. Different plants thrive in different types of soil, so it&#8217;s important to know what you&#8217;re working with. Take a sample of your soil to your local nursery or cooperative extension office for analysis.</p>

<h2>2. Choose the Right Plants</h2>
<p>When selecting plants for your garden, choose those that are well-suited to your climate and growing conditions. Consider factors such as sunlight exposure, moisture levels, and temperature fluctuations when making your choices.</p>

<h2>3. Plan Your Layout</h2>
<p>A well-planned layout can make all the difference in creating an aesthetically pleasing garden landscape. Consider elements such as symmetry, color schemes, and focal points when planning out your design.</p>

<h2>4. Incorporate Hardscaping Elements</h2>
<p>Hardscaping elements such as pathways, retaining walls, and fountains can add interest and structure to your garden landscape. Consider incorporating these elements into your design for added visual appeal.</p>

<h2>5. Pay Attention to Scale</h2>
<p>Pay attention to scale when selecting plants and hardscaping elements for your garden landscape. A large plant may overwhelm a small space while too many small elements may clutter larger areas.</p>

<h2>6. Use Complimentary Colors</h2>
<p>Select colors that compliment each other when choosing plants for your garden landscape. This can create a cohesive and visually pleasing look.</p>

<h2>7. Add Year-Round Interest</h2>
<p>Consider adding elements to your garden landscape that will provide interest throughout the year, such as evergreen trees or shrubs, ornamental grasses, or winter-blooming flowers.</p>

<h2>8. Incorporate Lighting</h2>
<p>Add lighting elements to highlight key areas in your garden landscape such as pathways or water features. This not only provides added visual interest but also enhances safety and security.</p>

<h2>9. Consider Maintenance</h2>
<p>When selecting plants and hardscaping elements for your garden landscape, consider the amount of maintenance required to keep them looking their best. Choose low-maintenance options if you have limited time or resources.</p>

<h2>10. Enjoy the Process!</h2>
<p>Above all, enjoy the process of creating your stunning garden landscape! Gardening is a wonderful hobby that can provide endless rewards both physically and emotionally.</p>

<p>In conclusion, by following these 10 tips you can create a beautiful and visually appealing garden landscape that will bring joy for years to come!</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/07/14/10-tips-for-creating-a-stunning-garden-landscape/index.html">10 Tips for Creating a Stunning Garden Landscape</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/07/14/10-tips-for-creating-a-stunning-garden-landscape/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
