<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>popular Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:50:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Popular Herbal Teas That Can Be Made From Herbs Grown In Your Backyard</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/06/07/popular-herbal-teas-that-can-be-made-from-herbs-grown-in-your-backyard/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/06/07/popular-herbal-teas-that-can-be-made-from-herbs-grown-in-your-backyard/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 19:06:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[herbal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[herbs:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=68</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Popular Herbal Teas That Can Be Made From Herbs Grown In Your Backyard If you&#8217;re someone who loves gardening and enjoys a good cup of tea, then growing your own herbs for herbal teas is an excellent idea. Not only will you have fresh, organic herbs at your disposal, but you&#8217;ll be able to experiment [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/07/popular-herbal-teas-that-can-be-made-from-herbs-grown-in-your-backyard/index.html">Popular Herbal Teas That Can Be Made From Herbs Grown In Your Backyard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348cc9_PopularHerbalTeasThatCanBeMadeFromHerbsGrownInYourBackyard.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Popular Herbal Teas That Can Be Made From Herbs Grown In Your Backyard</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re someone who loves gardening and enjoys a good cup of tea, then growing your own herbs for herbal teas is an excellent idea. Not only will you have fresh, organic herbs at your disposal, but you&#8217;ll be able to experiment with different flavors and blends.</p>

<h2>Mint Tea</h2>

<p>Mint is one of the easiest herbs to grow and it&#8217;s perfect for making refreshing and soothing tea. Peppermint has a strong menthol flavor which makes it great for digestion issues while spearmint has a milder taste that can help reduce stress levels. Simply add fresh mint leaves to boiling water or let them steep in cold water overnight for a refreshing beverage.</p>

<h2>Lemon Balm Tea</h2>

<p>Lemon balm is another easy-to-grow herb that can be used to make delicious tea. It has a subtle lemon flavor that&#8217;s perfect for calming nerves and reducing anxiety. Additionally, lemon balm contains antioxidants that can help boost your immune system. To make lemon balm tea, simply steep fresh leaves in hot water for 5-10 minutes.</p>

<h2>Chamomile Tea</h2>

<p>Chamomile is a popular herb that&#8217;s known for its calming properties. It has been used as a natural remedy for insomnia, anxiety and depression. Chamomile also helps relieve digestive problems like bloating and indigestion. You can grow chamomile in your backyard easily from seeds or seedlings purchased from nurseries or online stores.</p>

<h2>Rosemary Tea</h2>

<p>Rosemary is an herb often used in cooking but it also makes an excellent tea when steeped in hot water with some honey or lemon juice added to it. Rosemary tea is known for its antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties which can help with improving memory and concentration, reducing stress levels, and fighting off respiratory infections.</p>

<h2>Lavender Tea</h2>

<p>Lavender is a fragrant herb that&#8217;s commonly used in aromatherapy. However, it also makes a great tea that can help reduce anxiety and promote relaxation. Lavender tea is easy to make by steeping fresh or dried lavender flowers in hot water for 5-10 minutes.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Growing your own herbs in your backyard is a wonderful way to enjoy fresh, organic herbs while having fun experimenting with different flavors and blends. With just a few simple steps, you can easily grow the herbs mentioned above and create delicious herbal teas that are both healthy and refreshing.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/06/07/popular-herbal-teas-that-can-be-made-from-herbs-grown-in-your-backyard/index.html">Popular Herbal Teas That Can Be Made From Herbs Grown In Your Backyard</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/06/07/popular-herbal-teas-that-can-be-made-from-herbs-grown-in-your-backyard/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
