<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>weather Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:49:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 16:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harvest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather Fall is the perfect time to start planning your garden for the upcoming season. Cooler weather and shorter days make it an ideal time to grow vegetables that thrive in these conditions. Here are some great options to consider: Kale Kale is a hardy vegetable [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html">Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64349413_PlanningYourFallHarvestWithVegetablesThatLoveCoolerWeather.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</h1>

<p>Fall is the perfect time to start planning your garden for the upcoming season. Cooler weather and shorter days make it an ideal time to grow vegetables that thrive in these conditions. Here are some great options to consider:</p>

<h2>Kale</h2>
<p>Kale is a hardy vegetable that can withstand cooler temperatures, making it a great choice for fall gardening. It&#8217;s also packed with nutrients like vitamin C, vitamin K, and beta carotene. Kale can be grown from seeds or transplants and will continue to produce leaves throughout the season.</p>

<h2>Spinach</h2>
<p>Another leafy green that loves cooler weather is spinach. Rich in iron and other essential vitamins, spinach is easy to grow from seed or transplants. Plant it early enough in the fall so that it has time to mature before winter arrives.</p>

<h2>Carrots</h2>
<p>Carrots are a root vegetable that love cooler weather, making them perfect for fall gardens. They&#8217;re packed with vitamins A and C and are easy to grow from seed. Just make sure they have plenty of space to grow deep into the soil.</p>

<h2>Broccoli</h2>
<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a hearty vegetable that loves cooler weather, broccoli is an excellent choice. It&#8217;s high in fiber, vitamin C, and other nutrients making it a healthy addition to any meal plan. Broccoli grows best from seeds planted directly in the ground.</p>

<h2>Cauliflower</h2>
<p>Cauliflower is another cool-weather crop that&#8217;s packed with vitamins and minerals like vitamin C, folate, and potassium. It can be grown from seeds or transplants but needs plenty of space between plants as they can get quite large.</p>

<h2>Brussels Sprouts</h2>
<p>Brussels sprouts are a member of the cabbage family and love cooler weather. They&#8217;re packed with vitamin C, folate, and fiber, making them a healthy choice for any meal plan. Plant them in early fall so they have time to mature before winter arrives.</p>

<h2>Cabbage</h2>
<p>Cabbage is another member of the brassica family that thrives in cooler weather. It&#8217;s high in vitamin C and can be grown from seeds or transplants. Make sure it has plenty of space between plants as cabbage can get quite large.</p>

<p>When planning your fall harvest garden, make sure to choose vegetables that love cooler weather like kale, spinach, carrots, broccoli, cauliflower, Brussels sprouts, and cabbage. These veggies are packed with nutrients and will keep you well-fed throughout the fall season.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/index.html">Planning your Fall Harvest with Vegetables that Love Cooler Weather</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/09/27/planning-your-fall-harvest-with-vegetables-that-love-cooler-weather/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
