<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>compost Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:48:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 18:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[every]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garden:]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[should]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin Gardening is a fun and rewarding hobby that allows you to grow fresh produce, beautiful flowers, and lush greenery in your yard. However, maintaining a garden can also generate a lot of waste – from grass clippings to fallen leaves to kitchen scraps. If you&#8217;re looking for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html">Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643492ac_WhyEveryGardenShouldHaveACompostBin.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</h1>

<p>Gardening is a fun and rewarding hobby that allows you to grow fresh produce, beautiful flowers, and lush greenery in your yard. However, maintaining a garden can also generate a lot of waste – from grass clippings to fallen leaves to kitchen scraps.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking for an eco-friendly way to dispose of this waste while simultaneously improving the health of your garden, consider investing in a compost bin. Here are just a few reasons why every garden should have one:</p>

<h2>Composting reduces waste</h2>

<p>According to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), yard trimmings and food residuals together constitute 28% of the solid waste generated in the United States. By composting these materials instead of sending them to landfill, you can significantly reduce your household&#8217;s environmental impact.</p>

<h2>Composting enriches soil</h2>

<p>The end result of composting is nutrient-rich soil that can be used as fertilizer for your plants. Compost adds organic matter back into the soil, improving its structure and water retention capabilities. This means healthier plants with stronger root systems that are better equipped to withstand droughts and other environmental stresses.</p>

<h2>Composting saves money</h2>

<p>By using homemade compost instead of store-bought fertilizers or soil amendments, you can save money on gardening supplies over time. In addition, if you&#8217;re already paying for municipal yard waste pickup or disposal services, composting at home allows you to divert some or all of this material from the landfill.</p>

<h2>Composting is easy</h2>

<p>You don&#8217;t need any special skills or equipment to start composting in your own backyard. All you really need is a container (such as a plastic bin) and some organic matter to get started. There are plenty of online resources available to help you troubleshoot any issues that may arise, such as compost that smells bad or isn&#8217;t breaking down properly.</p>

<h2>Composting benefits the environment</h2>

<p>In addition to reducing waste and greenhouse gas emissions associated with landfilling, composting also helps to mitigate climate change by sequestering carbon in the soil. According to the EPA, compost application can lead to a 5-10% increase in soil carbon levels over time.</p>

<p>In conclusion, adding a compost bin to your garden is an easy and effective way to reduce waste, save money, improve soil health, and benefit the environment. So why not give it a try?</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/index.html">Why Every Garden Should Have a Compost Bin</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/11/10/why-every-garden-should-have-a-compost-bin/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
