<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>household Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:48:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 08:41:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[household]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[items]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[planters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[upcycling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=71</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters Do you have some old household items that you no longer use? Instead of throwing them away, why not upcycle them into unique planters for your home or garden? Not only is this a great way to repurpose items and reduce waste, but it can [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html">DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348d14_DiyIdeasForUpcyclingOldHouseholdItemsIntoUniquePlanters.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</h1>

<p>Do you have some old household items that you no longer use? Instead of throwing them away, why not upcycle them into unique planters for your home or garden? Not only is this a great way to repurpose items and reduce waste, but it can also add a fun and creative touch to your decor.</p>

<h2>Mason Jars</h2>
<p>Mason jars are versatile containers that can be easily transformed into charming planters. Simply fill the jar with soil and plant herbs, succulents or small flowers. You can also glue pebbles or moss onto the outside of the jar for added texture.</p>

<h2>Tin Cans</h2>
<p>Empty tin cans are another popular choice for DIY planters. To create a rustic look, wrap twine around the outside of the can and tie it in place. Then fill with soil and plants, making sure to punch drainage holes in the bottom first.</p>

<h2>Buckets And Pails</h2>
<p>If you have an old bucket or pail lying around, why not turn it into a planter? This works particularly well for larger plants such as tomatoes or peppers. You may need to drill drainage holes in the bottom of the container before adding soil and planting.</p>

<h2>Coffee Mugs</h2>
<p>You don&#8217;t need fancy ceramic pots to display your plants &#8211; coffee mugs work just fine! Choose brightly colored mugs for a playful touch or vintage cups for a more classic look.</p>

<h2>Suitcases And Briefcases</h2>
<p>For a truly unique planter idea, try using an old suitcase or briefcase as a container. These work well for larger plants such as ferns or ivies. Simply fill the case with soil and plants, then leave it open or prop it up to show off your greenery.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>Upcycling old household items into planters is a fun and creative way to add some greenery to your home or garden. With just a little bit of creativity, you can turn almost anything into a unique planter that will be sure to impress your friends and family.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/index.html">DIY Ideas For Upcycling Old Household Items Into Unique Planters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/12/26/diy-ideas-for-upcycling-old-household-items-into-unique-planters/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
