<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>about Archives - Gardening</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../index.html</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:51:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Everything You Need To Know About Raised Bed Gardens</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/02/21/everything-you-need-to-know-about-raised-bed-gardens/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/02/21/everything-you-need-to-know-about-raised-bed-gardens/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 06:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[about]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[everything]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raised]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Everything You Need To Know About Raised Bed Gardens If you&#8217;re interested in gardening, you&#8217;ve probably heard of raised bed gardens. But what exactly are they, and why are they becoming so popular? In this post, we&#8217;ll answer all your questions about raised bed gardens. What is a raised bed garden? A raised bed garden [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/02/21/everything-you-need-to-know-about-raised-bed-gardens/index.html">Everything You Need To Know About Raised Bed Gardens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/643498dc_EverythingYouNeedToKnowAboutRaisedBedGardens.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Everything You Need To Know About Raised Bed Gardens</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re interested in gardening, you&#8217;ve probably heard of raised bed gardens. But what exactly are they, and why are they becoming so popular? In this post, we&#8217;ll answer all your questions about raised bed gardens.</p>

<h2>What is a raised bed garden?</h2>

<p>A raised bed garden is a type of garden that&#8217;s built above ground level. It consists of a large container or frame filled with soil, which is used to grow plants. The sides of the container can be made from various materials such as wood, brick or stone.</p>

<h2>What are the benefits of a raised bed garden?</h2>

<p>There are several benefits to using a raised bed garden:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Better drainage:</strong> Because the soil in a raised bed is elevated above ground level, it drains more easily than soil on flat ground. This means that your plants won&#8217;t become waterlogged and develop root rot.</li>
  <li><strong>Better soil quality:</strong> With traditional gardening methods, the soil can become compacted over time. A raised bed allows you to start with fresh soil that&#8217;s loose and nutrient-rich.</li>
  <li><strong>Easier access:</strong> Raised beds are typically built at waist height, which means you don&#8217;t have to bend down as much when planting or harvesting.</li>
  <li><strong>Better pest control:</strong> Because the plants are elevated off the ground, pests like slugs and snails have a harder time getting to them.</li>
</ul>

<h2>How do I build a raised bed garden?</h2>

<p>You can either purchase pre-made raised beds or build your own. If you decide to build your own, here&#8217;s what you&#8217;ll need:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Wooden boards or bricks to make the sides of the bed</li>
  <li>Screws or nails to hold the boards together</li>
  <li>A level to make sure the bed is even</li>
  <li>Soil and compost to fill the bed</li>
</ul>

<p>To build your raised bed garden, follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Determine the size and shape of your raised bed.</li>
  <li>Cut your wooden boards to size, or stack your bricks in a rectangular shape.</li>
  <li>Attach the wooden boards together using screws or nails. Make sure they&#8217;re level.</li>
  <li>Add soil and compost to fill the bed.</li>
</ol>

<h2>What should I plant in my raised bed garden?</h2>

<p>You can plant almost anything in a raised bed garden, but some plants do better than others. Here are a few ideas:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Vegetables:</strong> Tomatoes, peppers, lettuce, carrots, and beans all do well in raised beds.</li>
  <li><strong>Herbs:</strong> Basil, parsley, cilantro, and rosemary can add flavor to your meals.</ li >
  	<li><strong>Flowers: </ strong > Marigolds help deter pests from eating your vegetables while adding color and beauty to your garden. </ li >
    </ul>

<h2>Caring for Your Raised Bed Garden</h2>

<p>Raised beds require regular watering and weeding. You may also need to fertilize them periodically throughout the growing season. Be sure to keep an eye out for pests like aphids or caterpillars that can damage plants. If you notice any issues with your plants, take action quickly to prevent them from spreading.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Raised bed gardens are a great way to grow your own fruits, vegetables, and herbs. They offer numerous benefits over traditional gardening methods and are easy to build and maintain. With a little bit of planning and care, you can enjoy fresh produce from your raised bed garden all season long.</p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/02/21/everything-you-need-to-know-about-raised-bed-gardens/index.html">Everything You Need To Know About Raised Bed Gardens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/02/21/everything-you-need-to-know-about-raised-bed-gardens/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everything You Need to Know About Composting at Home</title>
		<link>./../../../2022/02/09/everything-you-need-to-know-about-composting-at-home/index.html</link>
					<comments>./../../../2022/02/09/everything-you-need-to-know-about-composting-at-home/index.html#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jerry Harvard]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 20:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[about]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[composting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[everything]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=45</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Everything You Need to Know About Composting at Home If you&#8217;re looking for a simple and effective way to reduce your household waste while also doing your part for the environment, composting at home is an excellent option. Composting involves breaking down organic materials such as food scraps, yard waste, and paper products into nutrient-rich [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/02/09/everything-you-need-to-know-about-composting-at-home/index.html">Everything You Need to Know About Composting at Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
    <figure class="wp-block-image size-full">
    <img decoding="async" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2023/04/64348b6e_EverythingYouNeedToKnowAboutCompostingAtHome.png" alt="" class="wp-image-12"/>
    </figure>
    
    
    
    <h1>Everything You Need to Know About Composting at Home</h1>

<p>If you&#8217;re looking for a simple and effective way to reduce your household waste while also doing your part for the environment, composting at home is an excellent option. Composting involves breaking down organic materials such as food scraps, yard waste, and paper products into nutrient-rich soil that can be used in gardens or landscaping. Not only does this process help divert waste from landfills, but it also provides a natural alternative to chemical fertilizers.</p>

<h2>Getting Started with Composting</h2>

<p>The first step in starting your own home composting system is choosing the right location. Ideally, you&#8217;ll want a spot that&#8217;s out of direct sunlight and has good drainage. You can purchase a compost bin or make one using wooden pallets or chicken wire.</p>

<p>Next, gather the materials you&#8217;ll need to get started:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Brown materials &#8211; such as dry leaves, straw, or shredded newspaper</li>
  <li>Green materials &#8211; including fruit and vegetable scraps, coffee grounds and filters, eggshells</li>
  <li>A shovel or pitchfork for turning the compost pile</li>
  <li>A water source to keep the pile moist </li>
</ul>

<h2>Composting Dos and Don&#8217;ts</h2>

<p>To ensure that your composting efforts are successful, here are some key dos and don&#8217;ts:</p>

<h3>Dos:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Mix green and brown materials in equal parts for optimal decomposition.</li>
  <li>Add water regularly to keep the pile moist but not soggy.</li>
  <li>Aerate the pile regularly by turning it with a pitchfork every few weeks.</li>
  <li>Pick up a composter thermometer to monitor the temperature of your pile. The ideal range is between 130-150 degrees Fahrenheit.</li>
</ul>

<h3>Don&#8217;ts:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Avoid adding meat, dairy, or oily foods to your compost pile, as they can attract pests and slow down decomposition.</li>
  <li>Don&#8217;t add pet waste, as it can contain harmful bacteria that may not break down in the composting process.</li>
  <li>Avoid adding weeds or diseased plants to your pile, as this can spread weed seeds or disease spores throughout your garden when you use the finished compost.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Troubleshooting Common Composting Problems</h2>

<p>Like any gardening endeavor, home composting may encounter some issues along the way. Here are some common problems and solutions:</p>

<h3>The Compost Pile Smells Bad:</h3>

<p>This usually means there&#8217;s an imbalance in the green/brown materials ratio. Add more dry brown materials such as leaves or shredded newspaper to balance it out and reduce odors.</p>

<h3>The Compost Pile is Too Dry:</h3>

<p>Add more water to moisten the pile or consider moving it to a shadier location with better moisture retention.</p>

<h3>The Compost Pile isn&#8217;t Breaking Down Fast Enough:</h3>

<p>If you want faster results, try chopping up your green materials into smaller pieces before adding them to the pile. You can also purchase a compost activator product that contains helpful microbes to speed up decomposition time.</p>


<h2>Using Your Finished Compost</h2>

<p>Your finished compost should be dark brown and crumbly with an earthy smell. Once ready, use it in place of chemical fertilizers for healthier soil and plants! </p>
    <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2022/02/09/everything-you-need-to-know-about-composting-at-home/index.html">Everything You Need to Know About Composting at Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Gardening</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../2022/02/09/everything-you-need-to-know-about-composting-at-home/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
